const arr = [{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A doctor checking a chest X-ray notices a rib having the subclavian artery on it. Which of the following ribs has the groove for this artery?","answers":[{"option":"2","bool":false},{"option":"6","bool":false},{"option":"3","bool":false},{"option":"4","bool":false},{"option":"1","bool":true}],"id":0},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"What is the type of epithelium found in the vocal cords of the larynx?","answers":[{"option":"Stratified cuboidal","bool":false},{"option":"Simple squamous","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous non-keratinized","bool":true},{"option":"Stratified squamous keratinized","bool":false},{"option":"Columnar ciliated","bool":false}],"id":1},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Pleural effusion is checked on X-ray at which of the following levels?","answers":[{"option":"Costophrenic angle","bool":true},{"option":"Cardiophrenic angle","bool":false},{"option":"Sternal angle","bool":false},{"option":"Base of the lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Infrasternal angle","bool":false}],"id":2},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is used to determine the pH of the buffer solution?","answers":[{"option":"Strong acid","bool":false},{"option":"Weak and strong acid","bool":false},{"option":"Weak acid","bool":false},{"option":"Weak base","bool":false},{"option":"Acid and conjugate base","bool":true}],"id":3},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following does not characterize the bronchopulmonary segment?","answers":[{"option":"Has its own vein","bool":true},{"option":"Pyramidal in shape","bool":false},{"option":"Has its own artery","bool":false},{"option":"Independent functional unit","bool":false},{"option":"Segmental bronchus","bool":false}],"id":4},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A 4-year-old boy presents to the emergency department with complaints of coughing and wheezing after swallowing 5 rupees coin. The pulmonologist used a bronchoscope to perform foreign body aspiration to remove the coin. What is the most expected place for trapping of the foreign body?","answers":[{"option":"Trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Right bronchus","bool":true},{"option":"Left bronchus","bool":false},{"option":"Lobule of lung","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchioles","bool":false}],"id":5},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"What is the level of bifurcation of the trachea?","answers":[{"option":"T3","bool":false},{"option":"Sternal angle","bool":true},{"option":"T6","bool":false},{"option":"Gastroesophageal junction","bool":false},{"option":"T4","bool":false}],"id":6},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2017","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is not a part of the superior mediastinum?","answers":[{"option":"Arch of the aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Brachiocephalic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Superior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Subclavian artery","bool":false},{"option":"Heart","bool":true}],"id":7},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 30-year-old patient presents to the emergency department with complaints of fever, chest pain, and blood-stained sputum. His blood culture shows lancet-shaped gram-positive diplococci. What is this organism?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus influenzae","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Klebsiella","bool":false},{"option":"Mycoplasma pneumoniae","bool":false}],"id":8},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of these substances is used to synthesize prostaglandins?","answers":[{"option":"Arginine","bool":false},{"option":"Arachidonic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Nitric oxide","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Oxygen","bool":false}],"id":9},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2017","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following cells of the lungs secrete surfactant?","answers":[{"option":"Endothelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Type 2 alveolar epithelial cells","bool":true},{"option":"Secretory cells","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous epithelial cells of trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Type 1 alveolar epithelial cells","bool":false}],"id":10},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2017","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of these represents the vital capacity?","answers":[{"option":"Tidal volume + expiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Tidal volume + inspiratory reserve volume + expiratory reserve volume","bool":true},{"option":"Tidal volume + inspiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Tidal volume + expiratory reserve volume + residual volume","bool":false},{"option":"Residual volume + tidal volume + expiratory reserve volume","bool":false}],"id":11},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following enzymes catalyzes the formation of bicarbonate ions from water and carbon dioxide in the blood?","answers":[{"option":"Protein kinase","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholinesterase","bool":false},{"option":"Carbonic anhydrase","bool":true},{"option":"Alkaline phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"Adenylate cyclase","bool":false}],"id":12},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"What is the most common route carbon dioxide takes to be transported to the cells?","answers":[{"option":"In the form of carbaminohemoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"In the form of bicarbonate ions","bool":true},{"option":"By dissolving in plasma","bool":false},{"option":"By binding to plasma proteins","bool":false},{"option":"In the form of carboxy hemoglobin","bool":false}],"id":13},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following does not drain into the thoracic duct?","answers":[{"option":"Right intercostal nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Left intercostal nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Left lower limb","bool":false},{"option":"Right lower limb","bool":false},{"option":"Left bronchomediastinal trunk","bool":false}],"id":14},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Caplan syndrome consists of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Asbestosis and tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Byssinosis and rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumoconiosis  and rheumatoid arthritis","bool":true},{"option":"Silicosis and tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Berriliosis","bool":false}],"id":15},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 27-year-old man is brought to the emergency department after he suffered from a stab wound injury in the abdomen. The wound continues up to the central tendon of the diaphragm. Which of the following structures passing through the diaphragm can be the source of hemorrhage?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior phrenic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior vena cava","bool":true},{"option":"Aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Azygos vein","bool":false},{"option":"Hemiazygos vein","bool":false}],"id":16},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"pH can be defined as the negative log of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrogen ion concentration","bool":true},{"option":"Weak acid","bool":false},{"option":"Hydroxyl ion concentration","bool":false},{"option":"Weak base","bool":false},{"option":"Strong acid","bool":false}],"id":17},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Bucket handle movement of which ribs lead to the increase in transverse diameter during inspiration?","answers":[{"option":"3-8","bool":false},{"option":"10-12","bool":false},{"option":"2-6","bool":false},{"option":"7-10","bool":true},{"option":"1-7","bool":false}],"id":18},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"What will be the potassium value of the patient suffering from respiratory acidosis resulting from brain trauma?","answers":[{"option":"2.5 mEq/L","bool":false},{"option":"3.5 mEq/L","bool":false},{"option":"6 mEq/L","bool":true},{"option":"4.5 mEq/L","bool":false},{"option":"4 mEq/L","bool":false}],"id":19},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 40-year-old female with a known case of the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) presents to the outpatient department with complaints of productive cough with sputum, fever with chills, and wheezing. Which of the following types of pneumonia is responsible for this?","answers":[{"option":"Typical pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Aspiration pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Atypical pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumoconiosis","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchopulmonary pneumonia","bool":false}],"id":20},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"In the 3rd week of development, notochord formation occurs that persists in adults as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Nucleus pulposus","bool":true},{"option":"Transverse process","bool":false},{"option":"Sternum","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebral arch","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebral body","bool":false}],"id":21},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following enzymes degrade sphingomyelin?","answers":[{"option":"Phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"Ceramidase","bool":false},{"option":"Sphingomyelinase","bool":true},{"option":"Glucocerebrosidase","bool":false},{"option":"Glucosidase","bool":false}],"id":22},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 70-year-old man presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of a bad cough and says, \"the chest appears suffocating to me and I am unable to breath due to chest tightness\". Which of the following is responsible for his symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Compensatory respiratory alkalosis","bool":false}],"id":23},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The body of the sternum joins with the manubrium of the sternum at the level of T4-T5, which corresponds to which of the following ribs?","answers":[{"option":"4","bool":false},{"option":"2","bool":true},{"option":"6","bool":false},{"option":"3","bool":false},{"option":"1","bool":false}],"id":24},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the simplest hydrophilic moiety factor in phospholipids?","answers":[{"option":"Hydroxyl","bool":true},{"option":"Sulfate","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Carbons","bool":false}],"id":25},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which type of cell in the respiratory system has cilia?","answers":[{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Columnar cell","bool":true},{"option":"Goblet cell","bool":false},{"option":"Basal cell","bool":false},{"option":"Brush cell","bool":false}],"id":26},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A young man presents to the nearby clinic with complaints of shortness of breath and cough with a copious amount of mucus production. He is found infertile and is diagnosed with immotile cilia syndrome. What is defective in this syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Nexin link","bool":false},{"option":"Dynein arms","bool":true},{"option":"Central pair of microtubules","bool":false},{"option":"Axoneme","bool":false},{"option":"Peripheral microtubules","bool":false}],"id":27},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which one of the following is a term used to describe a lack of sufficient oxygen delivered to the tissues?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Anoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxia","bool":true}],"id":28},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The increase in cardiac output during exercise is accompanied by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Sometimes decreased, sometimes increased pulmonary pressure","bool":false},{"option":"No increase in pulmonary pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in pulmonary pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Massive increase in pulmonary pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Slight increase in pulmonary pressure","bool":true}],"id":29},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"What is the key difference between thromboxane A2 and prostaglandins?","answers":[{"option":"Thromboxane A2 decreases platelet aggregation while prostaglandins increase it","bool":false},{"option":"Thromboxane A2 mediates pain while prostaglandins do not","bool":false},{"option":"Thromboxane A2 causes platelet aggregation while prostaglandins decrease it","bool":true},{"option":"Thromboxane A2 causes vasodilation while prostaglandins cause vasoconstriction","bool":false},{"option":"Thromboxane A2 mediates allergic reactions while prostaglandins do not","bool":false}],"id":30},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following types of cancer involves the chromosome 3p deletions and mutations in TP53, Rb?","answers":[{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Basal cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":true}],"id":31},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Acid-fast staining or Ziehl–Neelsen staining is used to rule out the presence of Mycobacterium tuberculosis, which appears red in this stain. Which of the following property enables it to appear red under this particular type of stain?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrophilic nature of its walls","bool":false},{"option":"Absorption of counter stain","bool":false},{"option":"Retention of dye due to the presence of mycolic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Discoloration by acid alcohol","bool":false},{"option":"Transmembrane channels in its walls","bool":false}],"id":32},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following organisms is most likely to cause pneumonia in an immunocompromised patient?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Mycoplasma","bool":false},{"option":"Legionella pneumophila","bool":true},{"option":"Haemophilus influenzae","bool":false}],"id":33},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"On examination of histological slides of the lung, students got confused between different bronchioles. Which of the following is the identifying feature that distinguishes respiratory bronchioles from other bronchioles?","answers":[{"option":"The type of epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"The number of cells","bool":false},{"option":"The presence of glands","bool":false},{"option":"The interrupted wall of lumen","bool":true},{"option":"The diameter of lumen","bool":false}],"id":34},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"The pulmonary alveoli are cup-shaped structures and are composed of many cells. Which of the following are the alveolar cells present in alveoli that are cuboidal in shape?","answers":[{"option":"Great alveolar cells","bool":true},{"option":"Squamous alveolar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar sac","bool":false},{"option":"Type 1 alveolar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar atria","bool":false}],"id":35},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following protein concentrations indicates that the fluid collected in the pleural cavity is an exudative fluid when serum protein content is normal?","answers":[{"option":"50 g/L","bool":true},{"option":"30 g/L","bool":false},{"option":"10 g/L","bool":false},{"option":"5 g/L","bool":false},{"option":"3 g/L","bool":false}],"id":36},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Gases such as oxygen and carbon dioxide cross the plasma membrane by which of the following methods?","answers":[{"option":"Secondary active transport","bool":false},{"option":"Facilitated diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Passive diffusion through the lipid bilayer","bool":true},{"option":"Primary active transport","bool":false},{"option":"Specific gas transport proteins","bool":false}],"id":37},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A patient came to the emergency department. His pulse and blood pressure were undetectable. While his history was being taken, the doctor came to know that the patient had severe hypertension. An immediate X-ray was ordered and it showed fluid in the pleural cavity following an aortic aneurysm and pleuritis. What condition would the patient most likely be suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Hemothorax","bool":true},{"option":"Hydrothorax","bool":false},{"option":"Chylothorax","bool":false},{"option":"Tension pneumothorax","bool":false},{"option":"Hydropneumothorax","bool":false}],"id":38},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following features clearly distinguishes bronchioles from bronchi under the light microscope?","answers":[{"option":"The type of cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"The type of glands","bool":false},{"option":"The presence of cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"The presence of smooth muscle","bool":false},{"option":"The absence of glands","bool":true},{"option":"The type of epithelium","bool":false}],"id":39},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"pH value can be determined by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"pH detector","bool":false},{"option":"pH balancer","bool":false},{"option":"pH electrode","bool":false},{"option":"pH spectrometer","bool":false},{"option":"pH meter","bool":true}],"id":40},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"During systole, what is the pressure of the pulmonary artery equal to?","answers":[{"option":"Right ventricle","bool":true},{"option":"Right atrium","bool":false},{"option":"Left atrium","bool":false},{"option":"Left ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Superior vena cava","bool":false}],"id":41},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"When is pulmonary resistance increased?","answers":[{"option":"Vagal inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Lungs are small","bool":false},{"option":"In sympathetic stimulation","bool":false},{"option":"In parasympathetic inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"During inspiration","bool":true}],"id":42},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"The central chemoreceptors are stimulated maximally by which of the following chemical substance?","answers":[{"option":"High concentration of bicarbonate ions","bool":false},{"option":"High concentration of CO₂","bool":false},{"option":"Low partial pressure of oxygen","bool":false},{"option":"High concentration of hydrogen ions","bool":true},{"option":"High pH in blood","bool":false}],"id":43},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"The students of first year MBBS are given a slide of the respiratory system. It shows all the usual layers: mucosa, submucosa, cartilage/muscular layer, and adventitia. Which of the following components of the respiratory airway has the greatest relative amount of smooth muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Larynx","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchioles","bool":false},{"option":"Trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchi","bool":true}],"id":44},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is helpful in differentiating the trachea from the esophagus?","answers":[{"option":"Epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"Submucosa","bool":false},{"option":"Adventitia","bool":false},{"option":"Glands","bool":false},{"option":"Blood vessels","bool":false}],"id":45},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The trachea bifurcates into two primary bronchi at which of the following levels?","answers":[{"option":"T1","bool":false},{"option":"T7","bool":false},{"option":"T6","bool":false},{"option":"T5","bool":true},{"option":"T2","bool":false}],"id":46},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The diffusion of gases increases even at normal partial pressure due to which reason?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased velocity","bool":false},{"option":"Increased surface area","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased solubility","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased surface area","bool":false},{"option":"Solubility of gas","bool":false}],"id":47},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following factors shifts the oxygen dissociation curve to the right?","answers":[{"option":"High pH","bool":false},{"option":"Strenuous exercise","bool":true},{"option":"Low temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Low concentration of 2,3 DPG","bool":false},{"option":"Fetal hemoglobin","bool":false}],"id":48},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is a characteristic feature of the twelfth rib?","answers":[{"option":"Costal groove","bool":false},{"option":"Neck of the rib","bool":false},{"option":"Single facet on head","bool":true},{"option":"Costal cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Angle of the rib","bool":false}],"id":49},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following correctly describes the first seven ribs?","answers":[{"option":"True ribs","bool":true},{"option":"Floating ribs","bool":false},{"option":"False ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Typical ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Atypical ribs","bool":false}],"id":50},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"During a tooth extraction procedure, a broken tooth accidentally fell into the respiratory passage. What is the most common site for the foreign body to dislodge?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchioles","bool":false},{"option":"Trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Terminal bronchus","bool":false},{"option":"Left bronchus","bool":false},{"option":"Right bronchus","bool":true}],"id":51},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) in adults is a deficiency of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Renin","bool":false},{"option":"CO2 tension","bool":false},{"option":"O2 tension","bool":true},{"option":"Angiotensin converting enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Surfactant","bool":false}],"id":52},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following does not play any role in the embryological development of the upper respiratory tract?","answers":[{"option":"Pharyngeal pouches","bool":false},{"option":"Pharyngeal clefts","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal placodes","bool":false},{"option":"Neural crest cells","bool":true},{"option":"Pharyngeal arches","bool":false}],"id":53},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following options correctly describes hypercapnia?","answers":[{"option":"Buildup of carbon dioxide in body fluids","bool":true},{"option":"Excess carbon dioxide excretion","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in negative ions of the plasma","bool":false},{"option":"Excess of oxygen in blood plasma","bool":false},{"option":"Buildup of bicarbonate ions in the blood plasma","bool":false}],"id":54},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"After which of the following weeks does the large cavity from the thorax to the pelvis develop?","answers":[{"option":"10th week","bool":false},{"option":"8th week","bool":false},{"option":"9th week","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":true},{"option":"7th week","bool":false}],"id":55},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Alveoli are cup-shaped structures having very thin walls through which gaseous exchange between blood and air takes place. What lies in the region between two adjacent alveoli?","answers":[{"option":"Alveolar phagocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Inter-alveolar septum","bool":true},{"option":"Alveolar ducts","bool":false},{"option":"Atrium","bool":false}],"id":56},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The bulk of carbon dioxide in the blood is carried in which of the following forms?","answers":[{"option":"Carbaminohemoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"Dissolved in blood","bool":false},{"option":"Bicarbonate ion in red blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Carbonic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Bicarbonate ion in plasma","bool":true}],"id":57},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Strong signals from which of the following centers limit the tidal volume thereby increasing the respiratory rate?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsal respiratory group of neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Apneustic centre","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumotaxic centre","bool":true},{"option":"Ventral respiratory group of neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Central chemoreceptors","bool":false}],"id":58},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 50-year-old female has experienced a 5 kg weightloss over the last 3 months. She recently developed low grade fever and cough with mucoid sputum production and after 2 weeks, she experienced blood streaked sputum. There are bilateral crackles in the left upper lobe on auscultation of the chest. The sputum smear shows bright red bacilli against a bluish background. Which of the following findings are most likely to be present in the sputum sample?","answers":[{"option":"Foreign body giant cells","bool":false},{"option":"Gram-negative bacilli","bool":false},{"option":"Acid-fast bacilli","bool":true},{"option":"Branching septate hyphae","bool":false},{"option":"Charcot-Leyden crystals","bool":false}],"id":59},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 12-year-old girl has a 7 year history of coughing, wheezing, and repeated attacks of difficulty in breathing. The attacks get more common during spring. During an episode of acute respiratory difficulty, physical examination shows that she is afebrile. Her lungs are hyper-resonant on percussion and chest radiograph shows increased lucency of all lung fields. Laboratory tests show an elevated serum IgE level and peripheral blood eosinophilia. Sputum sample is examined and it also has increased number of eosinophils. Which of the following histological features are most likely a characteristic feature of this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Dilatation of bronchi and loss of elastic tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Patchy consolidation in lung parenchyma","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammatory destruction of bronchiolar walls","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar and interstitial edema with sheets of macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Remodeling of airways with smooth muscle hyperplasia","bool":true}],"id":60},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following progresses from interstitial fibrosis, diffuse fibrosis to characteristic end-stage honeycomb appearance?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumoconiosis","bool":false},{"option":"Non specific interstitial pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Cryptogenic organizing pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Usual interstitial pneumonia","bool":true}],"id":61},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 14-year-old girl from a village presented with anorexia, weight loss, and lethargy for the past 5 weeks. She also had several episodes of abdominal pain. History revealed that drinking unpasteurized milk was quite common in her region. Which of the following organisms would most likely be the causative agent in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Mycobacterium leprae","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium ulcerans","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium bovis","bool":true},{"option":"Mycobacterium avium","bool":false}],"id":62},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following terms is used to describe a bluish-purple discoloration of the mucosa and the skin due to reduced hemoglobin content in the body?","answers":[{"option":"Anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Anorexia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxemia","bool":false},{"option":"Cyanosis","bool":true},{"option":"Hypoxia","bool":false}],"id":63},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following terms is used to indicate the benign neoplasm of glandular epithelial cells?","answers":[{"option":"Papilloma","bool":false},{"option":"Choriocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Polyp","bool":false},{"option":"Adenoma","bool":true}],"id":64},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which factor shifts the oxygen dissociation curve to the right?","answers":[{"option":"Decrease in hydrogen ion concentration","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in pH","bool":true},{"option":"Decrease in partial pressure of carbon dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in concentration of 2,3 bis-phosphoglycerate","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in temperature","bool":false}],"id":65},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A female patient was brought to the emergency department with chest pain. She was a known case of mediastinal lymphoma. Doppler's ultrasound revealed the presence of the milky fluid in the pleural cavity which points towards the obstruction of the thoracic duct by the tumor mass. Which of the following entities designates this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Suppurative pleuritis","bool":false},{"option":"Miliary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Chylothorax","bool":true},{"option":"Pneumothorax","bool":false},{"option":"Filariasis","bool":false}],"id":66},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"In which of the following conditions are cells unable to utilize oxygen?","answers":[{"option":"Increase in pH","bool":false},{"option":"Carbon monoxide poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased 2,3 bis-phosphoglycerate","bool":false},{"option":"Cyanide poisoning","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased hydrogen ion concentration","bool":false}],"id":67},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Exposure to which of the following is most likely to cause mesothelioma?","answers":[{"option":"Coal dust","bool":false},{"option":"Tobacco","bool":false},{"option":"Tin oxide","bool":false},{"option":"Silica","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestos","bool":true}],"id":68},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following carcinogens present in cigarettes accelerates heart rate and the activity of the nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Aromatic hydrocarbons","bool":false},{"option":"Nicotine","bool":true},{"option":"Asbestos","bool":false},{"option":"Silica","bool":false},{"option":"Nitric oxide","bool":false}],"id":69},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of lung cancer?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrocarbons","bool":false},{"option":"Tobacco","bool":true},{"option":"Radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Aromatic fumes","bool":false},{"option":"Sunlight","bool":false}],"id":70},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The peripheral chemoreceptors are stimulated maximally by which of the following chemical substance?","answers":[{"option":"High concentration of hydrogen ions","bool":false},{"option":"High level of bicarbonate ions","bool":false},{"option":"Low partial pressure of oxygen","bool":true},{"option":"High pH in blood","bool":false},{"option":"High concentration of CO2","bool":false}],"id":71},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the equation which defines that the pKa of an acid is numerically equal to the pH of the solution when the molar concentration of the acid and its conjugate base are equal?","answers":[{"option":"Haldane equation","bool":false},{"option":"Henderson-Hasselbalch equation","bool":true},{"option":"Hardy-Weinberg equation","bool":false},{"option":"Water dissociation constant","bool":false},{"option":"Michaelis-Menten equation","bool":false}],"id":72},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 16-year-old male came to the emergency department with shortness of breath and drowsiness. He was in respiratory distress. On the chest x-ray, there was atelectasis of the lungs due to air accumulation. There was no history of trauma or perforating injury. This clinical picture is mostly seen in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Traumatic pneumothorax","bool":false},{"option":"Spontaneous pneumothorax","bool":true},{"option":"Tension pneumothorax","bool":false},{"option":"Therapeutic pneumothorax","bool":false},{"option":"Hemopneumothorax","bool":false}],"id":73},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 29-year-old female presented to the outpatient department with fever and cough. She was evaluated with a chest x-ray. Which of the following is the standard position for obtaining a routine adult chest radiograph?","answers":[{"option":"Apical view","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral view","bool":false},{"option":"Anteroposterior (AP) view","bool":false},{"option":"Posteroanterior (PA) view","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral decubitus view","bool":false}],"id":74},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Asthma is characterized by reversible bronchoconstriction caused by airway hyperresponsiveness to a variety of stimuli. What is the fundamental abnormality in asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Exaggerated Th-2 response to environmental allergens","bool":true},{"option":"Increased mucous secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Exaggerated Th-1 response to environmental allergens","bool":false},{"option":"Mast cell mobilization","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased airway responsiveness","bool":false}],"id":75},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 60-year-old male, known case of type-2 diabetes for the last 20 years, presents in the emergency room with anorexia, vomiting, and flank pain for the last year. On examination, he is lethargic, with blood pressure 90/60 mmHg, pulse 100/minute, respiratory rate 24/minute, his chest and abdomen are unremarkable. His creatinine is 8 mg%. His random blood sugar is 70 mg%. Arterial blood gases show a pH of 7.2, pCO2 of 30mmHg, and HCO3 of 16 mEq/L. Urine DR is normal. What is the most likely diagnosis in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Diabetic ketoacidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Uremic acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Starvation ketoacidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Lactic acidosis","bool":false}],"id":76},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following types of hypoxia occurs when cells are destroyed by reactive oxygen species and can not utilize oxygen properly?","answers":[{"option":"Anemic hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Histotoxic hypoxia","bool":true},{"option":"Stagnant hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Ischemic hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Anemic hypoxia","bool":false}],"id":77},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"There is a person who has been consuming alcohol for a long time. His family wants him to get rid of this bad habit as it is injurious to health from a long-term perspective. He himself is well aware of the consequences but isn't able to just stop it all of a sudden. Which of the following terms is described as physical dependence of the body on some substance to function?","answers":[{"option":"Incontinence","bool":false},{"option":"Habituation","bool":false},{"option":"Dysfunction","bool":false},{"option":"Addiction","bool":true},{"option":"Rehabilitation","bool":false}],"id":78},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A female patient came to the outpatient department with chest pain. Her X-ray reports showed the hard mass in her right chest . Upon bronchoscopy, it was confirmed to be lung cancer. Which of the following is the most common site for tracheobronchial cancers to occur?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchopulmonary segment","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchi","bool":true},{"option":"Brochioles","bool":false},{"option":"Lung lobule","bool":false},{"option":"Alveoli","bool":false}],"id":79},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following statements is correct about the azygous vein?","answers":[{"option":"Arises from left ascending lumbar vein","bool":false},{"option":"It drains into the inferior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"It joins hemiazygos vein at T4 level","bool":false},{"option":"It ascends on the left side of the thorax","bool":false},{"option":"It passes from the aortic hiatus of the diaphragm","bool":true}],"id":80},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"In the lung parenchyma of a deceased patient, a few darkly stained cells were seen. Upon careful observation, they appear to have dark granules in their cytoplasm. A few students pointed out that there are some phagocytosing cells in the alveolar walls which engulf dust and carbon particles and therefore appear to be darker. Which of the following cells are they most likely be talking about?","answers":[{"option":"Type II pneumocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Type I pneumocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cells","bool":false},{"option":"Dust cells","bool":true}],"id":81},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is not true about rhinitis?","answers":[{"option":"Type-l hypersensitivity reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Histamine release","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Vasoconstriction","bool":true},{"option":"Nasal congestion","bool":false}],"id":82},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A person is nervous and is breathing rapidly. It can lead to which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Both respiratory acidosis and alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":true}],"id":83},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"What is a chronic inflammatory condition of the lung airways resulting in episodic airflow obstruction called?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Allergic rhinitis","bool":false},{"option":"Angioedema","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial lung disease","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":true}],"id":84},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following shifts the oxygen hemoglobin dissociation curve to the left?","answers":[{"option":"Fever","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in CO2","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in 2,3-biphosphoglycerate","bool":false},{"option":"Acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Fetal hemoglobin","bool":true}],"id":85},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 40-year-old female presents in the emergency room with severe cough, fever, and chest pain. Her COVID-19 PCR is positive. On examination, she is lethargic, with blood pressure 100/60mmHg, pulse 120/minute, respiratory rate 30/minute. Her chest is full of crepts. Arterial blood gases show pH of 7.1,  pCO2 of 60mmHg, and HCO3 of 30 mEq/L. What is the most likely diagnosis in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Mixed metabolic and respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Lactic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic ketoacidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Uremic ketoacidosis","bool":false}],"id":86},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"During severe exercise, the volume of air inspired and expired may increase to as great as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Vital capacity","bool":true},{"option":"Functional residual capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Inspiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Expiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Residual volume","bool":false}],"id":87},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"In the normal systemic arterial blood, the total quantity of oxygen is bound with hemoglobin and it is 96% saturated. Upon passing through the tissue capillaries, this amount is reduced and the hemoglobin is now 75% saturated with oxygen. What will be the partial pressure of oxygen (P02) in this blood in which hemoglobin is 75% saturated?","answers":[{"option":"60 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"80 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"100 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"20 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"40 mmHg","bool":true}],"id":88},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following muscles are involved in inspiration during pulmonary ventilation?","answers":[{"option":"Diaphragm and external intercostal muscles","bool":true},{"option":"Diaphragm and internal intercostal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Internal and external intercostal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Rectus abdominis and internal intercostal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Scalene muscles and internal intercostal muscles","bool":false}],"id":89},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Paradoxical breathing due to injury of the anterolateral chest wall is known as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Pigeon chest","bool":false},{"option":"Flail chest","bool":true},{"option":"Scoliosis","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Kyphosis","bool":false}],"id":90},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The cartilaginous, muscular, and connective tissue components of the trachea and lungs are derived from which of the following surrounding structures of the foregut?","answers":[{"option":"Endoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Splanchnic mesoderm","bool":true},{"option":"Neural crest cells","bool":false},{"option":"Ectoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Somatic mesoderm","bool":false}],"id":91},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"An infant born at the 24th week of gestation develops worsening respiratory distress. Her chest x-ray showed honeycomb appearance of the lungs. What will be the diagnosis of the infant?","answers":[{"option":"Agenesis of lung","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary hypoplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory lung","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital lung cysts","bool":true}],"id":92},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"During the discussion of the histology of sense organs, students were asked to identify the olfactory epithelium. Which of the following is correct about olfactory epithelium?","answers":[{"option":"Simple cuboidal","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudo-stratified columnar without goblet cells","bool":true},{"option":"Simple columnar ciliated","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudo-stratified columnar with goblet cells","bool":false},{"option":"Tall columnar with microvilli","bool":false}],"id":93},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 60-year-old man has had fever, night sweats, and a 7 kg weight loss over the past 4 months. In the past month, he has had episodes of hemoptysis. He dies of respiratory failure and hypoxemia. Infection with which of the following organisms is most likely to have produced these findings?","answers":[{"option":"Candida albicans","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Mycoplasma pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Influenza","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":true}],"id":94},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The capacity for a normal understanding of what people are feeling appears to be central to the human practice of medicine. This ability is best described as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Empathy","bool":true},{"option":"Emotional dissonance","bool":false},{"option":"Genetic characteristics","bool":false},{"option":"Personality types","bool":false},{"option":"Good auditory capacity","bool":false}],"id":95},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Respiratory acidosis occurs as a result of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Lung disease: causing increased retention of CO2","bool":true},{"option":"Kidney disease, causing increased retention of bicarbonate","bool":false},{"option":"Lung disease: causing increased exhalation of CO2","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney disease: causing increased excretion of bicarbonate","bool":false},{"option":"Increased bicarbonate infusion","bool":false}],"id":96},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 70-year-old male came to the outpatient department with shortness of breath and productive cough of yellow sputum. He also had a clinical history of high-grade fever for 5 days. On the chest x-ray, there was fluid inside the pleural cavity. Which of the following is the most probable etiology of fluid in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Congestive heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false}],"id":97},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The decrease in oxygen affinity of hemoglobin when blood pH falls is called which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Haldane's effect","bool":false},{"option":"Bohr's effect","bool":true},{"option":"Hawthorn effect","bool":false},{"option":"Henry's effect","bool":false},{"option":"Hamburger effect","bool":false}],"id":98},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is a measure of the overall disease burden expressed as a number of years lost due to ill health, disability, or early death adopted by the World Health Organization (WHO) in 2000?","answers":[{"option":"YLL (Years of Lost Life)","bool":false},{"option":"Morbidity","bool":false},{"option":"Disability-adjusted life years (DALYs)","bool":true},{"option":"YLD (Years Lost to Disability)","bool":false},{"option":"Surveillance","bool":false}],"id":99},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The ability of the lungs to return to their normal size after stretching is known as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Compliance","bool":false},{"option":"Capacitance","bool":false},{"option":"Resistance","bool":false},{"option":"Resilience","bool":false},{"option":"Elasticity","bool":true}],"id":100},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The trachea is part of the conducting portion of the respiratory system. It is composed of the mucosa lined by pseudostratified ciliated columnar epithelium, glands in submucosa, cartilage and adventitia. Which of the following structures has the same histological appearance as the trachea?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory bronchioles","bool":false},{"option":"Extra-pulmonary bronchi","bool":true},{"option":"Intra-pulmonary bronchi","bool":false},{"option":"Pre-terminal bronchioles","bool":false},{"option":"Terminal bronchioles","bool":false}],"id":101},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 50-year-old pregnant female presents in the emergency room with vomiting and upper abdominal pain for the last 2 days. On examination, she is lethargic, with blood pressure 90/60 mmHg, pulse 120/minute, respiratory rate 30/minute, and 101°F temperature. Her chest is clear while her abdomen is mildly tender in the epigastrium. Her random blood sugar is 400mg% and arterial blood gases show a pH of 7.1, pCO2 of 2OmmHg, and HCO3 of 10 mEq/L. Urine shows 3+ ketones. What is the most likely diagnosis in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic ketoacidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Fasting ketoacidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Lactic acidosis","bool":false}],"id":102},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"No single test can secure a diagnosis of asthma. Which of the following is the most helpful and preferred method for establishing the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Arterial blood gases","bool":false},{"option":"Pulse oximeter","bool":false},{"option":"Chest x-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Spirometry","bool":true},{"option":"C.T scan of chest","bool":false}],"id":103},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Each molecule of hemoglobin can transport how much oxygen?","answers":[{"option":"16 atoms of oxygen","bool":false},{"option":"4 atoms of oxygen","bool":false},{"option":"2 molecules of oxygen","bool":false},{"option":"4 molecules of oxygen","bool":true},{"option":"8 molecules of oxygen","bool":false}],"id":104},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 32-year-old man after a road traffic accident is having trouble breathing. Upon reaching the emergency department his lung function test was done and his functional residual capacity was found to be reduced. This capacity indicates which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"The amount of air remaining in the lungs after maximum expiration","bool":false},{"option":"The amount of air inspired and expired during each normal breath","bool":false},{"option":"Combination of inspiratory reserve volume and tidal volume","bool":false},{"option":"Amount of air expelled out after each normal expiration","bool":false},{"option":"The amount of air remaining in the lungs after normal expiration","bool":true}],"id":105},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 55-year-old male was admitted to the hospital with complaints of shortness of breath for a day, he had a history of hip replacement surgery and he was immobile. He was a suspected case of pulmonary embolism. Which is the gold standard investigation for the diagnosis of pulmonary embolism?","answers":[{"option":"V/Q scan","bool":false},{"option":"Echocardiography","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary angiography","bool":true},{"option":"Chest x-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Electrocardiography","bool":false}],"id":106},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"During an exam, the teacher asked the student that in which period of lung maturation, the cuboidal respiratory bronchioles change into thin, flat cells, the blood-air barrier is established and respiration becomes possible. What should be the answer of the student?","answers":[{"option":"Late fetal period to one year","bool":false},{"option":"2 years to 8 years","bool":false},{"option":"5 to 17 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"24 weeks to late fetal period","bool":true},{"option":"16 to 25 weeks","bool":false}],"id":107},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The respiratory part of the respiratory system is responsible for the diffusion of gases at the level of alveoli. Which type of cell is responsible for exchanging gases?","answers":[{"option":"Type 1 pneumocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Dust cells","bool":false},{"option":"Clara cells","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Type 2 pneumocytes","bool":false}],"id":108},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A one-week-old infant was brought by his mother complaining of frequent drooling of saliva and immediate regurgitation of milk when fed. Which of the following could be the diagnosis of the child?","answers":[{"option":"Tracheal bronchus","bool":false},{"option":"Laryngo-tracheoesophageal cleft","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital lung cysts","bool":false},{"option":"Tracheo-esophageal fistula","bool":true},{"option":"Tracheal stenosis","bool":false}],"id":109},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 42-year-old male patient comes to the emergency with complaints of fever with chills and cough for one week with a large amount of sputum and pain in the chest. Community-acquired pneumonia is suspected. What is the most common cause in such a case?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Legionella pneumophila","bool":false},{"option":"Moraxella catarrhalis","bool":false}],"id":110},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The rate of diffusion of a substance is inversely proportional to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Square root of  the molecular weight","bool":true},{"option":"Solubility","bool":false},{"option":"Cross-sectional area of the fluid","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Partial pressure difference between the fluids","bool":false}],"id":111},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The lymphatic drainage of lung roots is via which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Subpleural plexus","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial lymphatic plexus","bool":false},{"option":"Parasternal lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracic duct","bool":false},{"option":"Deep lymphatic plexus","bool":true}],"id":112},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is a feature that is present only in the thoracic vertebra?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior articular facet","bool":false},{"option":"Costal facet","bool":true},{"option":"Intervertebral foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Superior articular facet","bool":false},{"option":"Laminae","bool":false}],"id":113},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 32-year-old lady presents with a 2-day history of shortness of breath, fever, and cough. On examination, she is tachypneic, dyspneic, and shows low blood oxygen saturation. There are no signs of cardiac failure. Chest x-ray shows bilateral lung infiltrates. Which of the following best describes the lung morphology on microscopy?","answers":[{"option":"Eosinophils and mast cells in abundance","bool":false},{"option":"Large, dilated alveoli with bullae formation","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestos bodies in macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Collapsed alveoli with hyaline membranes","bool":true},{"option":"Epithelioid granulomas with caseous necrosis","bool":false}],"id":114},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The hemoglobin bound to oxygen in the normal systemic arterial blood is 98% saturated. Upon passing through the tissue capillaries, this is reduced to 75% saturation. How much oxygen is transported from the lungs to the tissues by every 100 ml of blood flow?","answers":[{"option":"20 ml","bool":false},{"option":"10 ml","bool":false},{"option":"15 ml","bool":false},{"option":"40 ml","bool":false},{"option":"05 ml","bool":true}],"id":115},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following compounds is the most effective at maintaining the physiological pH?","answers":[{"option":"Bicarbonate buffer","bool":true},{"option":"Phosphate buffer","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium","bool":false}],"id":116},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The partial pressure of oxygen in the venous blood of a 20-year-old athlete is found to be 40 mmHg. What will be his hemoglobin saturation in this blood sample?","answers":[{"option":"25%","bool":false},{"option":"50%","bool":false},{"option":"40%","bool":false},{"option":"97%","bool":false},{"option":"75%","bool":true}],"id":117},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"In a section of lung tissue consisting predominantly of alveoli, a tubule about 2 mm in diameter is observed that contains smooth muscle and cartilage in its wall. Which of the following is the tubule discussed above?","answers":[{"option":"Trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchus","bool":true},{"option":"Alveolar sac","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiole","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar duct","bool":false}],"id":118},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 25-year-old male was admitted to the ward with complaints of shortness of breath for a day. He had a history of long hours travel. There is a positive family history of thrombosis in his first-degree relative. On investigation, a chest x-ray shows Westermark's sign and Hampton's hump signs. Which is the most probable diagnosis of these findings?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":true},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Atelectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestosis","bool":false}],"id":119},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The triradiate ligament of the head of the rib connects which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Neck of rib to transverse process of vertebra","bool":false},{"option":"Neck of rib to spinous process","bool":false},{"option":"Head of rib to two adjacent vertebrae","bool":true},{"option":"Tubercle of rib to tip of transverse process","bool":false},{"option":"Crest of rib to superior transverse process","bool":false}],"id":120},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"What is the pH of water?","answers":[{"option":"5","bool":false},{"option":"9","bool":false},{"option":"11","bool":false},{"option":"7","bool":true},{"option":"3","bool":false}],"id":121},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"As one ascends to higher than 3000 meters above sea level, what will be the changes in alveolar P02 and PCO2?","answers":[{"option":"Decrease in P02, decrease In PCO2","bool":true},{"option":"Increase in both P02 and PCO2","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in P02, increase In PCO2","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in P02, decrease In PCO2","bool":false},{"option":"No change","bool":false}],"id":122},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"On examination of tracheal slides, students observe mixed types of glands in the submucosa. Which of the following types of glands are these?","answers":[{"option":"Simple tubulo-alveolar glands","bool":false},{"option":"Branched tubulo-alveolar glands","bool":true},{"option":"Branched alveolar glands","bool":false},{"option":"Branched tubular glands","bool":false},{"option":"Simple tubular glands","bool":false}],"id":123},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 25-year-old man has a routine chest x-ray as a part of the visa process. His chest x-ray reveals a rounded, very high-density structure over the right lung. The given explanation best corresponds to which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Fat","bool":false},{"option":"Bone","bool":false},{"option":"Fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Metal","bool":true},{"option":"Gas","bool":false}],"id":124},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 40-year-old man presents with high-grade fever (102°F), productive cough, and chest pain. On auscultation, breath sounds on the lower right chest are very loud, high pitched with a gap in between inspiration and expiration, and expiration is longer than inspiration. Which of the following is most likely to be the type of breath sounds?","answers":[{"option":"Vesicular breath sounds","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchial vesicular breath sounds","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchial breath sounds","bool":true},{"option":"Added breath sounds","bool":false},{"option":"Tracheal breath sounds","bool":false}],"id":125},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"An interalveolar septum consists of two layers of squamous epithelial cells with blood capillary and specialized cells called which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Basal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Receptor cells","bool":false},{"option":"Dust cells","bool":true},{"option":"Sustentacular cells","bool":false},{"option":"Conical cells","bool":false}],"id":126},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 32-year-old male underwent a chest x-ray due to a job process. His chest x-ray was unremarkable. How the rotation of chest x-ray can be assessed?","answers":[{"option":"By counting the ribs","bool":false},{"option":"By identifying spine behind the heart","bool":false},{"option":"By looking at the orientation of ribs","bool":false},{"option":"By looking at the sternal ends of the clavicles","bool":true},{"option":"By looking at the lucency of lungs","bool":false}],"id":127},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Pacemaker cells for setting the respiratory rate are present in which of the following area?","answers":[{"option":"Pre-Botzinger complex","bool":true},{"option":"Pneumotaxic center","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal respiratory group of neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Apneustic center","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral cortex","bool":false}],"id":128},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is correct about the superior thoracic inlet of the thorax?","answers":[{"option":"An asymmetrical shape","bool":false},{"option":"An oblong shape","bool":false},{"option":"An anteroposterior diameter greater than transverse diameter","bool":false},{"option":"A transverse diameter equal to the anteroposterior diameter","bool":false},{"option":"A transverse diameter greater than anteroposterior diameter","bool":true}],"id":129},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Pulmonary arteries emerge from the pulmonary trunk at which level?","answers":[{"option":"Fourth intercostal space","bool":false},{"option":"First costal cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Third costal cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Second costal cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Sternal angle","bool":true}],"id":130},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Community-acquired pneumonia is mostly caused by specific bacteria. The most common organism can be diagnosed in the lab by which of the following test?","answers":[{"option":"On the Gram's staining","bool":true},{"option":"Growth on the chocolate agar","bool":false},{"option":"Type of hemolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Bacitracin sensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Optochin sensitivity","bool":false}],"id":131},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is a characteristic feature of the thoracic vertebra?","answers":[{"option":"Foramen transversarium","bool":false},{"option":"Bifid spinous process","bool":false},{"option":"Facet for the dens","bool":false},{"option":"Heart shaped body","bool":true},{"option":"Dens","bool":false}],"id":132},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A patient comes into the emergency department with a rib fracture. His breathing is painful, so he is taking rapid, small breaths. His respiratory rate is 40/min and his tidal volume is 200 ml. What would be his minute respiratory volume?","answers":[{"option":"4600 ml/min","bool":false},{"option":"200 ml/min","bool":false},{"option":"400 ml/min","bool":false},{"option":"8000 ml/min","bool":true},{"option":"2000 ml/min","bool":false}],"id":133},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The first two posterior intercostal arteries arise from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Arch of aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Costocervical trunk","bool":true},{"option":"Ascending aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Brachiocephalic trunk","bool":false}],"id":134},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"In prolapse of the intervertebral disc, pressure is exerted on which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Azygous vein","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Vertebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior thoracic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Intercostal artery","bool":false}],"id":135},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 30-year-old female, now 20-weeks pregnant, presents in the emergency room with anorexia, vomiting, and upper abdominal pain for the last 1 month. On examination, she is lethargic, with blood pressure 90/60 mmHg, pulse 120/minute, respiratory rate 30/minute. Her chest is clear while abdomen is mildly tender in epigastrium. Her random blood sugar is 70 mg% and arterial blood gases show a pH of 7.3, pCO2 of 30mmHg, and HCO3 of 16 mEq/L. Urine shows no ketones. What is the most likely diagnosis in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Starvation ketoacidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Lactic acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic ketoacidosis","bool":false}],"id":136},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"While explaining the stages of maturation of lungs, the teacher showed a histological slide of the lung in which branching had continued to form terminal bronchioles. There were no respiratory bronchioles or alveoli present. Which of the following stage is it?","answers":[{"option":"Canalicular","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar","bool":false},{"option":"Terminal sac","bool":false},{"option":"Post natal","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudoglandular","bool":true}],"id":137},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"When foreign objects are aspirated into the trachea, they will usually pass into the right primary bronchus because of which of the following reasons?","answers":[{"option":"It is at right angle to the left","bool":false},{"option":"It Is more curved, longer and smaller than the left","bool":false},{"option":"It is wider. straighter and shorter than the left","bool":true},{"option":"It lies at a higher level than the left","bool":false},{"option":"It is straighter, longer and larger than the left","bool":false}],"id":138},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"What is the common pathology in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)?","answers":[{"option":"Right arterial hypertrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid artery blockage","bool":false},{"option":"Left ventricular hypertrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Right ventricular hypertrophy","bool":true},{"option":"Left arterial hypertrophy","bool":false}],"id":139},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is present in the superior mediastinum?","answers":[{"option":"Arch of aorta","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchus","bool":false},{"option":"Descending aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Phrenic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Larynx","bool":false}],"id":140},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The amount of air remaining in the lungs even after forced expiration is known as?","answers":[{"option":"Expiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Inspiratory capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Inspiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Residual volume","bool":true},{"option":"Expiratory capacity","bool":false}],"id":141},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is a characteristic of the left lung?","answers":[{"option":"Horizontal fissure","bool":false},{"option":"Lingula of the lung","bool":true},{"option":"A groove for superior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Three lobar bronchi","bool":false},{"option":"A larger capacity than right lung","bool":false}],"id":142},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 45-year-old male was diagnosed with a severe right middle lobe infection of the lung. Where on the anterior chest wall, would you auscultate the right middle lobe?","answers":[{"option":"Sixth intercostal space","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth intercostal space","bool":true},{"option":"Second intercostal space","bool":false},{"option":"Seventh intercostal space","bool":false},{"option":"Superior to middle third of the clavicle","bool":false}],"id":143},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Compensated respiratory acidosis will have which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"A high CO2, low pH, low bicarbonate","bool":false},{"option":"A low C02, low pH, high bicarbonate","bool":false},{"option":"A low CO2, high pH, high bicarbonate","bool":false},{"option":"A high CO2, low pH, high bicarbonate","bool":true},{"option":"A high CO2, high pH, high bicarbonate","bool":false}],"id":144},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A 46-year-old woman goes to the physician for a routine health maintenance examination. On physical examination, there are no remarkable findings. Her body mass index is 22. She does not smoke. A tuberculin skin test is positive. A chest radiograph shows a solitary, 3-cm left upper lobe mass. The mass is removed during thoracotomy by wedge resection. The microscopic appearance of this lesion shows granulomas. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Lung abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Primary adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis infection","bool":true},{"option":"Pulmonary infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary hamartoma","bool":false}],"id":145},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the musical sound of the high frequency produced in larger airways due to vibrations in the bronchial wall from airflow velocity and is one of the most common symptoms of chronic asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Stridor","bool":false},{"option":"Conducted sounds","bool":false},{"option":"Wheezing","bool":true},{"option":"Rales","bool":false},{"option":"Crepitation","bool":false}],"id":146},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"In medical sciences, the patient is generally assessed through a biopsychosocial model. In which of the following aspect, there is an emphasis on cultural, environmental, and familial influences on expression and experience of illness?","answers":[{"option":"Cultural model","bool":false},{"option":"Ecological model","bool":false},{"option":"Social model","bool":true},{"option":"Psychological model","bool":false},{"option":"Biological model","bool":false}],"id":147},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Regarding the structure and functions of the alveoli of the lung, which of the following is mismatched?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumocyte type Il-->stem cell for more pneumocyte types 1 and 2","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumocyte (alveolar cell) type 1-->cytoplasm through which gaseous exchange occurs","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar macrophage-->removes inhaled particulates that reach the alveolus","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumocyte type II-->secretes pulmonary surfactant","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary surfactant-->increases surface tension within alveoli","bool":true}],"id":148},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Stimulation of which of the following center leads to active expiration?","answers":[{"option":"Ventral respiratory group of neurons","bool":true},{"option":"Apneustic center","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumotaxic center","bool":false},{"option":"Central chemoreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal respiratory group of neurons","bool":false}],"id":149},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"pH can be kept constant with the help of which of the following solutions?","answers":[{"option":"Super-saturated solution","bool":false},{"option":"Unsaturated solution","bool":false},{"option":"Strong acid solution","bool":false},{"option":"Buffer solution","bool":true},{"option":"Saturated solution","bool":false}],"id":150},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following pressure differences is responsible for the distention of the lungs?","answers":[{"option":"Airway closing pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Transthoracic pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Transpulmonary pressure","bool":true},{"option":"Airway opening pressure","bool":false}],"id":151},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Glomus cells present in the carotid and aortic bodies sense the partial pressure of oxygen in the blood. As the PO2 falls below 60 mmHg, these cells start to depolarize and eventually release neurotransmitters to activate the nerve. What is the basic mechanism by which glomus cells (chemoreceptors) depolarize?","answers":[{"option":"Closure of potassium channels","bool":true},{"option":"Opening of sodium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Opening of calcium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Closure of sodium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Opening of chloride channels","bool":false}],"id":152},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"1 gram of hemoglobin carries which of the following amounts of oxygen?","answers":[{"option":"1.35 ml","bool":false},{"option":"1 ml","bool":false},{"option":"1.34 ml","bool":true},{"option":"15 ml","bool":false},{"option":"20.1 ml","bool":false}],"id":153},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is not found in the interalveolar septum?","answers":[{"option":"Dust cells","bool":false},{"option":"Blood capillaries","bool":false},{"option":"Reticular fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Elastic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophills","bool":true}],"id":154},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is not a feature of the right main bronchus?","answers":[{"option":"It is 6 centimeters in length","bool":true},{"option":"It forms at the level of T4 vertebra","bool":false},{"option":"It lies posterior to the arch of aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Azygos vein arches posteriorly superior to it","bool":false},{"option":"It is more vertical than the left bronchus","bool":false}],"id":155},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Where is the olfactory epithelium found?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral walls of the nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Pharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Roof of the nasal cavity","bool":true},{"option":"Floor of the nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Medial walls of the nasal cavity","bool":false}],"id":156},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Thromboxane A2 is primarily represented by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Olfactory epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Platelets","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Mast cells","bool":false}],"id":157},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following represents the mechanism of action of the nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs?","answers":[{"option":"It inhibits cyclooxygenase pathway","bool":true},{"option":"It inhibits lipoxygenase pathway","bool":false},{"option":"It helps in the formation of prostaglandins","bool":false},{"option":"It helps in metabolizing arachidonic acid","bool":false},{"option":"It helps in the formation of steroids","bool":false}],"id":158},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"How much carbon dioxide is transferred per 100 ml of blood from the tissues to the lungs?","answers":[{"option":"20 ml","bool":false},{"option":"7 ml","bool":false},{"option":"52 ml","bool":false},{"option":"48 ml","bool":false},{"option":"4 ml","bool":true}],"id":159},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following molecular substances plays an important role in the adhesion-rolling phase of the leukocytes recruitment?","answers":[{"option":"Leukotrienes","bool":false},{"option":"Histaminase","bool":false},{"option":"C3b receptor","bool":false},{"option":"L, P and E selectins","bool":true},{"option":"Tumor necrosis factor","bool":false}],"id":160},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"What percentage of carbondioxide is carried in the form of bicarbonates in the plasma?","answers":[{"option":"97%","bool":false},{"option":"70%","bool":true},{"option":"10%","bool":false},{"option":"30%","bool":false},{"option":"50%","bool":false}],"id":161},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A patient presented to the emergency department with a respiratory rate of 8 breaths/min and was drowsy. His attendant told the doctor that he reported a stiff chest and had been unable to breathe properly. During further investigation, the doctor came to know that the patient had been suffering from emphysema. Which of the following conditions is most likely be the case?","answers":[{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis followed by respiratory compensation","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":true}],"id":162},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Celiac and stellate ganglions are the sympathetic ganglions. Which of the following ganglions is also included in this category?","answers":[{"option":"Otic ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal vagus nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Ciliary ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal root ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Ganglion impar","bool":true}],"id":163},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is not a bronchodilator?","answers":[{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-histamine","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-adrenergic drugs","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":true},{"option":"Levalbuterol","bool":false}],"id":164},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following statements is wrong regarding the internal thoracic artery?","answers":[{"option":"It arises from the third part of the subclavian artery","bool":true},{"option":"It runs posterior to upper six costal cartilages","bool":false},{"option":"Musculophrenic artery arises from the internal thoracic artery as its terminal branch","bool":false},{"option":"It gives rise to anterior intercostal arteries","bool":false},{"option":"It runs superficial to the vagus nerve","bool":false}],"id":165},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is correct about the role of Clara cells in reducing surface tension and prevention of collapse of airways?","answers":[{"option":"By secreting surfactant","bool":true},{"option":"By engulfing microorganisms","bool":false},{"option":"By producing mucus","bool":false},{"option":"By replacing the damaged cells","bool":false},{"option":"By their ciliary activity","bool":false}],"id":166},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"In which of the following weeks does the respiratory diverticulum (lung bud) appear as an outgrowth from the ventral wall of the foregut?","answers":[{"option":"7th","bool":false},{"option":"6th","bool":false},{"option":"8th","bool":false},{"option":"4th","bool":true},{"option":"5th","bool":false}],"id":167},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A child developed a common cold during his trip to northern areas and his parents are worried because the child has been a patient of asthma, but after taking complete medications it was cured. They read it somewhere that there are some structural changes that occur in the airway of asthmatic patients. What are the structural changes that develop in patients with asthma and how do they increase the risk of asthma recurrence?","answers":[{"option":"Increased inflammation in bacterial infections","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth muscle hypertrophy which increase chances of reversible bronchoconstriction","bool":true},{"option":"Alveolar walls degenerate causing less gaseous exchange","bool":false},{"option":"Increased sensitivity followed by fainting and blue lips","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar capillaries are constricted that collapse of bronchioles","bool":false}],"id":168},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Asthma is characterized by reversible bronchoconstriction caused by airway hyperresponsiveness to a variety of stimuli. Which of the following are risk factors for the development of asthma?","answers":[{"option":"High birth weight","bool":false},{"option":"Exposure to alcohol","bool":false},{"option":"High body-mass-index","bool":false},{"option":"Exposure to radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Exposure to air-borne allergens","bool":true}],"id":169},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Chronic bronchitis is characterized by the destruction of smooth muscle and elastic tissue leading to permanent dilatation of airways. Which of the following are the major morphological changes seen in chronic bronchitis?","answers":[{"option":"Slight increase in goblet cell number but markedly so in small airways","bool":false},{"option":"Increased mucosal gland depth compared to the thickness of the wall between the epithelium and the cartilage","bool":true},{"option":"Smooth muscle hypertrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Predominant lymphocyte infiltration","bool":false},{"option":"Reid index of 0.4 is normal and is observed in chronic bronchitis","bool":false}],"id":170},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Asthma is characterized by chest tightness, wheezing, sputum production, cough, and airway hyperresponsiveness. Which one of the following is the most characteristic factor of bronchial asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Reversible lower airway constriction","bool":true},{"option":"Symptoms are the same for every person with asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Persistent symptoms","bool":false},{"option":"Irreversible lower airway constriction","bool":false},{"option":"Destruction of smooth muscle","bool":false}],"id":171},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following statements is incorrect regarding the embryonic development of vertebrae?","answers":[{"option":"Vertebrae develop from sclerotome portions of somites","bool":false},{"option":"Caudal and cranial ends of adjacent sclerotomes fuse","bool":false},{"option":"Notochord remnants are in the form of nucleus pulposus","bool":false},{"option":"Sclerotomes migrate around notochord in the 6th week","bool":true},{"option":"Mesenchymal cells between sclerotomes form intervertebral discs","bool":false}],"id":172},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"In the right lung, oblique fissure separates which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Superior lobe from posterior lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Middle lobe from inferior lobe","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior lobe from posterior lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Superior lobe from middle lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Superior lobe from inferior lobe","bool":false}],"id":173},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the most common age for the development of atopic asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Childhood","bool":true},{"option":"Teenage","bool":false},{"option":"Old age","bool":false},{"option":"Adulthood","bool":false},{"option":"Neonatal","bool":false}],"id":174},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"The esophagus lies medial to the aorta in which of the following regions?","answers":[{"option":"Middle mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"The lower part of thoracic cavity just before it enters the abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Superior mediastinum","bool":true},{"option":"Root of the neck","bool":false}],"id":175},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"What does empathy mean in a doctor-patient relationship?","answers":[{"option":"Doctor should feel what the patient feels","bool":false},{"option":"Doctor should be careful","bool":false},{"option":"Doctor should be ignorant towards the patient's feelings","bool":false},{"option":"Doctor should understand what the patient is feeling","bool":true},{"option":"Doctor should not listen to the patient","bool":false}],"id":176},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"When the PO2 falls below 73 mmHg in alveolar air, which of the following occurs in the lungs?","answers":[{"option":"Expansion of alveoli","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased physiological shunt","bool":false},{"option":"Damage to type-1 pneumocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Constriction of blood vessels adjacent to alveoli","bool":true},{"option":"Nitrogen content increases","bool":false}],"id":177},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the structure that leaves the most pronounced impression on the right lung of the cadaver?","answers":[{"option":"Right vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Right common carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Azygous vein","bool":true},{"option":"Thoracic aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Right phrenic nerve","bool":false}],"id":178},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is related to persistent asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Irreversible bronchoconstriction of lower airways","bool":false},{"option":"Reversible bronchoconstriction of upper airways","bool":false},{"option":"Reversible bronchoconstriction of lower airways","bool":true},{"option":"Irreversible bronchoconstriction of upper airways","bool":false},{"option":"Permanent dilation of airways","bool":false}],"id":179},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following best describes the flail chest?","answers":[{"option":"First rib is fractured","bool":false},{"option":"More than 3 ribs are fractured at 2 places","bool":true},{"option":"Multiple ribs are fractured","bool":false},{"option":"Rib is fractured at the costal cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"More than 3 ribs are fractured at one place","bool":false}],"id":180},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"What is the reason behind respiration being abdominal in infants?","answers":[{"option":"Obliquity of ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Increased elasticity of chest wall","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of accessory cervical ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Horizontal predisposition of ribs","bool":true},{"option":"Bucket handle movement of ribs","bool":false}],"id":181},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following structure contains the greatest number of elastic fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Alveolar duct","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory bronchioles","bool":false},{"option":"Interalveolar septum","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar capillaries","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar sac","bool":true}],"id":182},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the correct X-ray orientation for chest lesions?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral view","bool":false},{"option":"Supine view","bool":false},{"option":"Posteroanterior view","bool":true},{"option":"Anteroposterior errect view","bool":false},{"option":"Anteroposterior view","bool":false}],"id":183},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following represents the tidal volume?","answers":[{"option":"The volume that remains in the lungs after forced expiration","bool":false},{"option":"The volume of air inhaled or exhaled during normal breathing","bool":true},{"option":"The volume exhaled in forced expiration","bool":false},{"option":"The maximum amount of air that can be inhaled","bool":false},{"option":"The volume that remains in the lungs after normal expiration","bool":false}],"id":184},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following represents pressure change in the thoracic cage during inspiration?","answers":[{"option":"More positive than +4  mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"More negative than 0.4  mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"More negative than -4 mm of Hg","bool":true},{"option":"More negative pressure than +2  mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"More negative than -2  mm of Hg","bool":false}],"id":185},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following represents compliance of both the lungs?","answers":[{"option":"600 ml/cm of H2O","bool":false},{"option":"110 ml/cm of H2O","bool":false},{"option":"50 ml/cm of H2O","bool":false},{"option":"200 ml/cm of H2O","bool":true},{"option":"400 ml/cm of H2O","bool":false}],"id":186},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following events only occurs in the forced inspiration?","answers":[{"option":"Relaxation of internal intercostals","bool":false},{"option":"Elevation of 2-7 ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Elevation of first rib","bool":true},{"option":"Contraction of diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Contraction of external intercostal muscles","bool":false}],"id":187},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following represents arterial partial pressure of oxygen?","answers":[{"option":"55 mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"20 mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"70 mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"75 mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"95 mm of Hg","bool":true}],"id":188},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following types of mediastinum consists of esophagus, thoracic duct, and sympathetic chain?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior mediastinum","bool":true},{"option":"Middle mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Superior mediastinum","bool":false}],"id":189},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"In a chest X-ray, a doctor sees a rib that articulates with both the manubrium and the body of the sternum. Which of the following is an atypical feature of this rib?","answers":[{"option":"Tuberosity","bool":false},{"option":"Neck","bool":false},{"option":"Tubercle for serratus anterior","bool":true},{"option":"Costal groove","bool":false},{"option":"Single facet on head","bool":false}],"id":190},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"A patient had tuberculosis and was advised anti-tuberculosis therapy but stopped after 7 days on the advice of the physician. He had developed pleuritis as tuberculosis has extended into the cavity. What other conditions can cause pleuritis?","answers":[{"option":"All of these","bool":true},{"option":"Mediastinal lymphadenitis","bool":false},{"option":"Lung carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Loffler's pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Pericarditis","bool":false}],"id":191},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is an inappropriate statement regarding respiratory bronchioles?","answers":[{"option":"Lack glands in its walls","bool":false},{"option":"Lack goblet cells","bool":false},{"option":"First part of the respiratory portion","bool":false},{"option":"Have an interruption of alveoli in its walls","bool":false},{"option":"Lack clara cells","bool":true}],"id":192},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2016","1st-year/respiratory/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is not a distinguishing feature between bronchus and bronchiole?","answers":[{"option":"Diameter of lumen","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of smooth muscles","bool":true},{"option":"Presence of glands","bool":false},{"option":"Type of cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Type of epithelium","bool":false}],"id":193},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is the major component of surfactant?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrosides","bool":false},{"option":"Gangliosides","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphatidyl lecithin","bool":false},{"option":"Dipalmitoyl phosphatidylcholine","bool":true}],"id":194},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these can not be measured by spirometry?","answers":[{"option":"Vital capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Inspiratory capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Tidal volume","bool":false},{"option":"Expiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Residual volume","bool":true}],"id":195},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is used to measure pH?","answers":[{"option":"pH scale","bool":false},{"option":"pH color","bool":false},{"option":"pH electrode","bool":false},{"option":"pH detector","bool":false},{"option":"pH meter","bool":true}],"id":196},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"What is the term used for the type of hypoxia that includes the disruption of oxygen usage of the cell by the toxic substances, even when there is high oxygen saturation?","answers":[{"option":"Circulatory hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Anemic hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxic hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Stagnant hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Histotoxic hypoxia","bool":true}],"id":197},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Where is the apex of the lung located?","answers":[{"option":"Below root of neck","bool":false},{"option":"Above 1st rib","bool":true},{"option":"Below clavicle","bool":false},{"option":"Below C1","bool":false},{"option":"Above 2nd rib","bool":false}],"id":198},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following leads to the bucket handle movement of the ribs during inspiration?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral movement of vertebral ends","bool":false},{"option":"Depression of vertebral ends of ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Elevation of shafts of ribs","bool":true},{"option":"Medial movement of vertebral ends","bool":false},{"option":"Elevation of sternal end","bool":false}],"id":199},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which movement is involved in the increase in vertical diameter of the thorax during inspiration?","answers":[{"option":"Bucket handle movement","bool":false},{"option":"Downward movement of diaphragm","bool":true},{"option":"Downward movement of ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Upward movement of diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Pump handle movement","bool":false}],"id":200},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following regions of mediastinum consists of the esophagus, trachea, and thoracic duct?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Superior mediastinum","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Middle mediastinum","bool":false}],"id":201},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Up to how many weeks can it take for a Mycobacterium tuberculosis culture to turn positive?","answers":[{"option":"2 days","bool":false},{"option":"4 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"7 days","bool":false},{"option":"7 weeks","bool":true},{"option":"4 days","bool":false}],"id":202},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Paralysis of the diaphragm is caused due to injury of?","answers":[{"option":"Supraclavicular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Phrenic nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Esophageal plexus","bool":false}],"id":203},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Chocolate agar contains which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Potato extract","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Nystatin","bool":false},{"option":"NAD","bool":true},{"option":"Iron","bool":false}],"id":204},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is responsible for the impairment of oxygen delivery to the tissues?","answers":[{"option":"Carbon monoxide poisoning","bool":true},{"option":"Running a marathon at sea level","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Previous history of cyanide poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"Doing exercise early in the morning","bool":false}],"id":205},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following drugs include transient memory loss as its side effect?","answers":[{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampin","bool":false},{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":true},{"option":"Pyrazinamide","bool":false}],"id":206},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following cells is dome-shaped and produces surfactant?","answers":[{"option":"Epithelial cell","bool":false},{"option":"Goblet cell","bool":false},{"option":"Type 2 pneumocyte","bool":false},{"option":"Clara cell","bool":true},{"option":"Type 1 pneumocyte","bool":false}],"id":207},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of these is not found in the plane of sternal angle?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary trunk bifurcation","bool":false},{"option":"Bifurcation of trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Brachiocephalic trunk","bool":true},{"option":"Arch of azygos vein","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic arch","bool":false}],"id":208},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is the volume remaining in the lungs after forceful exhalation?","answers":[{"option":"Total lung volume","bool":false},{"option":"Functional residual capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Tidal volume","bool":false},{"option":"Residual volume","bool":true},{"option":"Expiratory capacity","bool":false}],"id":209},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"The phrenic nerve is accompanied by which of the following arteries?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior epigastric artery","bool":false},{"option":"Internal thoracic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Pericardiophrenic artery","bool":true},{"option":"Superior epigastric artery","bool":false},{"option":"Musculophrenic artery","bool":false}],"id":210},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A doctor performs a surgery at the superior border of the intercostal space, causing pain. Which structure is damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Intercostal vessels","bool":true},{"option":"Epigastric vein","bool":false},{"option":"Intercostal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Hemiazygous vein","bool":false},{"option":"Azygous vein","bool":false}],"id":211},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which metabolic imbalance is seen in respiratory alkalosis?","answers":[{"option":"Na only","bool":false},{"option":"K only","bool":false},{"option":"Ca and K","bool":true},{"option":"Ca only","bool":false},{"option":"Ca and Na","bool":false}],"id":212},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Cardiac output is increased during strenuous exercise. How is the increased blood flow accommodated by pulmonary circulation?","answers":[{"option":"With decrease in pulmonary arterial pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Without large increase in pulmonary arterial pressure","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"With increase in pulmonary arterial pressure","bool":false},{"option":"With large increase in systemic arterial pressure","bool":false}],"id":213},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following statements is correct about zone 3 of pulmonary blood flow?","answers":[{"option":"Alveolar capillary pressure remains greater than alveolar air pressure","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"It is present in the apices of lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar air pressure remains greater than alveolar capillary pressure","bool":false},{"option":"It receives intermittent blood flow","bool":false}],"id":214},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"What is the total compliance of lungs in milliliters?","answers":[{"option":"1000","bool":false},{"option":"200","bool":true},{"option":"600","bool":false},{"option":"800","bool":false},{"option":"400","bool":false}],"id":215},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Caseating granulomas are found in tuberculosis. This is an example of which type of hypersensitivity?","answers":[{"option":"Type 3","bool":false},{"option":"Type 4","bool":true},{"option":"Type 1 (delayed)","bool":false},{"option":"Type 2","bool":false},{"option":"Type 1 (immediate)","bool":false}],"id":216},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following sets of ribs exhibits the bucket handle movement during inspiration?","answers":[{"option":"Ribs 7 to 10","bool":true},{"option":"Floating ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Ribs 1 to 9","bool":false},{"option":"Attached ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Ribs 1-2","bool":false}],"id":217},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A surgeon, while performing surgery, ligated the thoracic duct. Which of the following lymph drainage is not affected by this ligation?","answers":[{"option":"Diaphragmatic nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Left parasternal nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Left brachiomediastinal trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Right intercostal nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Left jugular trunk","bool":false}],"id":218},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which equation shows that pH of a solution is equal to its pKa when the acid and base are in equal concentrations?","answers":[{"option":"Water dissociation equation","bool":false},{"option":"Hardy Weinberg equation","bool":false},{"option":"Henderson-Hasselbalch equation","bool":true},{"option":"Torricelli's theorem","bool":false},{"option":"pH log equation","bool":false}],"id":219},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"What is the pressure difference between alveolar pressure and pleural pressure called?","answers":[{"option":"Interpleural pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Atmospheric pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Interpulmonary pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Transpulmonary pressure","bool":true},{"option":"Intrapleural pressure","bool":false}],"id":220},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"The pump handle movement of the rib cage involves which of the following ribs?","answers":[{"option":"2 to 10","bool":false},{"option":"7 to 10","bool":false},{"option":"2 to 6","bool":true},{"option":"7 to 12","bool":false},{"option":"1 to 7","bool":false}],"id":221},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"What is the term for the 8th to the 16th week of the respiratory system development stage?","answers":[{"option":"Terminal sac stage","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar stage","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudoglandular stage","bool":true},{"option":"Embryonic stage","bool":false},{"option":"Canalicular stage","bool":false}],"id":222},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Which of the following structures passes through the diaphragm with the esophagus?","answers":[{"option":"Phrenic nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Right vagus nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Sympathetic trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracic duct","bool":false},{"option":"Azygos vein","bool":false}],"id":223},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is the serous membrane covering the lungs?","answers":[{"option":"Pleura","bool":true},{"option":"Pericardium","bool":false},{"option":"Mesothelium","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelium","bool":false}],"id":224},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is not responsible for increasing sympathetic activity?","answers":[{"option":"Phenylephrine","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Pilocarpine","bool":true},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false}],"id":225},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which type of joint is found between the bodies of adjacent vertebrae?","answers":[{"option":"Synchondrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pivot","bool":false},{"option":"Cartilaginous","bool":false},{"option":"Synovial","bool":false},{"option":"Symphysis","bool":true}],"id":226},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is not an intrinsic muscle of the respiratory system?","answers":[{"option":"Serratus anterior","bool":true},{"option":"Diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Internal intercostal","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"External intercostal","bool":false}],"id":227},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"What is the normal value of pulmonary capillary pressure?","answers":[{"option":"2 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"5 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"7 mmHg","bool":true},{"option":"75 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"100 mmHg","bool":false}],"id":228},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Pigeon-shaped chest is associated with which disease?","answers":[{"option":"Asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false}],"id":229},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is true about the histology of brush cells?","answers":[{"option":"They are columnar cells with microvilli at the apical surface","bool":true},{"option":"They are cuboidal cells with microvilli at the basal surface","bool":false},{"option":"They are cuboidal cells with microvilli at the apical surface","bool":false},{"option":"They are squamous cells with microvilli at the apical surface","bool":false},{"option":"They are columnar cells with microvilli at the lateral surface","bool":false}],"id":230},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is not a part of the respiratory zone of the respiratory system?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory bronchioles","bool":false},{"option":"Terminal bronchioles","bool":true},{"option":"Atria","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar sac","bool":false},{"option":"Alveoli","bool":false}],"id":231},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"From which of the following structures does the diaphragm originate?","answers":[{"option":"Pleural membranes, costal cartilages, and the lumbar vertebrae","bool":false},{"option":"Lumbar vertebrae, sacrum, and the sternum","bool":false},{"option":"Lumbar vertebrae, pleural membranes, and the sacrum","bool":false},{"option":"Lumbar vertebrae, costal cartilages, and the sternum","bool":true},{"option":"Pleural membranes, costal cartilages, and the sternum","bool":false}],"id":232},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following structures is derived from the frontonasal prominence?","answers":[{"option":"Sides of the nose","bool":false},{"option":"The intermaxillary segment","bool":false},{"option":"Tip of the nose","bool":false},{"option":"Bridge of the nose","bool":true},{"option":"The nasal septum","bool":false}],"id":233},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"At what age should Bacillus Calmette–Guérin (BCG) be given?","answers":[{"option":"4 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"6 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"At birth","bool":true},{"option":"2 years","bool":false},{"option":"14 weeks","bool":false}],"id":234},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is involved in the increase in anteroposterior diameter?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Sternum","bool":true},{"option":"Upper costal lines","bool":false},{"option":"Lower costal lines","bool":false}],"id":235},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is incorrect for thyroid cartilage?","answers":[{"option":"Largest cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Thyrohyoid membrane connects to its upper border","bool":false},{"option":"Hyaline cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Has oblique line on the posterior surface","bool":true},{"option":"Vocal cord attaches to posterior surface","bool":false}],"id":236},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is attached to the tip of the xiphoid process?","answers":[{"option":"Diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Linea alba","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Coastal cartilages","bool":false},{"option":"Rectus abdominis","bool":false}],"id":237},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"What is correct regarding the right pulmonary artery?","answers":[{"option":"Carry oxygenated blood","bool":false},{"option":"Gives off branch to superior lobe before entering the root of lung","bool":true},{"option":"Bifurcate from pulmonary trunk at xiphoid level","bool":false},{"option":"Goes to opposite lung","bool":false},{"option":"Descend into lung anterolateral to main bronchus","bool":false}],"id":238},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"A procedure is performed on a man to remove the fluid in the pleural cavity. The patient feels pain when the needle inserts into the pleural membranes. Which of the following nerve is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Intercostal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Phrenic nerve","bool":false}],"id":239},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is a direct-acting cholinergic agonist?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Organophosphorous","bool":false},{"option":"Pilocarpine","bool":true},{"option":"Neostigmine","bool":false},{"option":"Physostigmine","bool":false}],"id":240},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following drugs is used for asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Inhaled corticosteriod","bool":true},{"option":"Oral corticosteriod","bool":false},{"option":"Sildenafil","bool":false},{"option":"Pilocarpine","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":241},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is present in azurophilic granules?","answers":[{"option":"Alkaline phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"Collagenase","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrolase","bool":false},{"option":"Myeloperoxidase","bool":true},{"option":"Collagen","bool":false}],"id":242},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is the main action of epinephrine at low doses?","answers":[{"option":"Pupil constriction","bool":false},{"option":"Salivary secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Increase heart contraction","bool":true},{"option":"Increased gut motility","bool":false},{"option":"Pupil dilation","bool":false}],"id":243},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"A patient presents to the emergency department with an acid smell or acetone breath. Which of the following is the person suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Central diabetes","bool":false},{"option":"Achalasia","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic ketoacidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Diabetic insipidus","bool":false}],"id":244},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following occurs as a result of hyperventilation?","answers":[{"option":"Excretion of vapors","bool":false},{"option":"Carbon dioxide excretion","bool":true},{"option":"Oxygen stress","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Volatile acid excretion","bool":false}],"id":245},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"In which of the following structures, circular cartilage rings are found?","answers":[{"option":"Alveolar sac","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory bronchiole","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar duct","bool":false},{"option":"Alveoli","bool":false},{"option":"Trachea","bool":true}],"id":246},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"What is the duration of the canalicular stage in the development of the lungs?","answers":[{"option":"Week 16 - week 26","bool":true},{"option":"Week 4 - week 8","bool":false},{"option":"Week 26 - week 36","bool":false},{"option":"Week 6 - week 16","bool":false},{"option":"Week 36 - week 40","bool":false}],"id":247},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"In which developmental week, mesoderm starts segmentation?","answers":[{"option":"4th","bool":false},{"option":"3rd","bool":true},{"option":"5th","bool":false},{"option":"7th","bool":false},{"option":"6th","bool":false}],"id":248},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is not a part of the posterior mediastinum?","answers":[{"option":"Thoracic duct","bool":false},{"option":"Trachea","bool":true},{"option":"Azygous vein","bool":false},{"option":"Splanchnic nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false}],"id":249},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of the chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)?","answers":[{"option":"Fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Environmental pollution","bool":false},{"option":"Aging","bool":false},{"option":"Dust","bool":false},{"option":"Smoking","bool":true}],"id":250},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Where do the sternal glands lie?","answers":[{"option":"Beside internal thoracic artery","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior to intercostal spaces","bool":false},{"option":"Right to internal jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior to thoracic duct","bool":false}],"id":251},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following structures is compressed by the Hiatal hernia?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior left ventricular wall","bool":true},{"option":"Aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Right phrenic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Right atrium","bool":false}],"id":252},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which structure lies at the midline of the thoracic inlet?","answers":[{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracic duct","bool":false},{"option":"Phrenic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal nerves","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":253},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following statements regarding the anatomical identification of the scalene tubercle is correct?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior surface of the first rib","bool":false},{"option":"Superior surface of the twelfth rib","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior surface of the tenth rib","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior surface of the twelfth rib","bool":false},{"option":"Superior surface of the first rib","bool":true}],"id":254},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which of the following stages of lobar pneumonia is characterized by the disintegration of erythrocytes and the presence of a grayish-brown exudate?","answers":[{"option":"Resolution","bool":false},{"option":"Gray hepatization","bool":true},{"option":"Congestion","bool":false},{"option":"Red hepatization","bool":false},{"option":"Abscess formation","bool":false}],"id":255},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Which part of the lungs is primarily affected by bronchiectasis?","answers":[{"option":"Upper lobe of the left lung","bool":false},{"option":"Lower lobes of both lungs","bool":true},{"option":"Upper lobes of both lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Middle lobe of the right lung","bool":false},{"option":"Lower lobe of the right lung","bool":false}],"id":256},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"Diffuse alveolar damage is the histological hallmark of which of the following respiratory conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Acute respiratory distress syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Coal workers’ pneumoconiosis","bool":false},{"option":"Transfusion-associated lung injury","bool":false},{"option":"Distal acinar emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease","bool":false}],"id":257},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2017"],"question":"What is the partial pressure of oxygen in alveoli at sea level?","answers":[{"option":"569 mm Hg","bool":false},{"option":"40 mm Hg","bool":false},{"option":"104 mm Hg","bool":true},{"option":"760 mm Hg","bool":false},{"option":"47 mm Hg","bool":false}],"id":258},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Heart is a circulatory organ that lies in which of the following mediastinum?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior","bool":false},{"option":"Superior","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior","bool":false},{"option":"Middle","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior","bool":false}],"id":259},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"A surgeon accidentally severed the thoracic duct during the surgery. Which of the following will not be affected by this laceration?","answers":[{"option":"Diaphragmatic node","bool":false},{"option":"Left parasternal node","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Left bronchomediastinal trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Right intercostal lymph node","bool":true}],"id":260},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What is the term used for the solution that resists the small changes in pH?","answers":[{"option":"Sugar solution","bool":false},{"option":"Buffer solution","bool":true},{"option":"Super saturated solution","bool":false},{"option":"Salt solution","bool":false},{"option":"Saturated solution","bool":false}],"id":261},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of the following anti-tubercular drugs requires pyridoxine as its antidote?","answers":[{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampin","bool":false},{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":true},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrazinamide","bool":false}],"id":262},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of the following drugs and their side effects is incorrectly matched?","answers":[{"option":"Pyrazinamide -> hypoglycemia","bool":true},{"option":"Isoniazid -> peripheral neurotoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampin -> harmless red urine color","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol -> optic neuritis","bool":false},{"option":"Streptomycin -> ototoxicity","bool":false}],"id":263},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of the following drugs has hyperuricemia as its side effect?","answers":[{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampin","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrazinamide","bool":true},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false}],"id":264},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What is the mode of action of rifampin?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibits RNA dependent DNA polymerase","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits synthesis of arabinogalactan","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits mycolic acid synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits DNA dependent RNA polymerase","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":265},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is not correct regarding the boundaries of mediastinum?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior boundary - abdomen","bool":true},{"option":"On each side - lungs and pleura","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior boundary - sternum","bool":false},{"option":"Superior boundary - thoracic inlet","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior boundary - vertebral column","bool":false}],"id":266},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"How many tobacco compounds are found in natural tobacco plant or when it is burnt?","answers":[{"option":"Over 3900","bool":true},{"option":"Over 2000","bool":false},{"option":"Around 1000","bool":false},{"option":"Around 100","bool":false},{"option":"Below 50","bool":false}],"id":267},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What is the cause of acute respiratory distress syndrome in adults?","answers":[{"option":"Carbon dioxide tension","bool":false},{"option":"Oxygen tension","bool":true},{"option":"Lack of surfactant in alveoli","bool":false},{"option":"Deficiency of angiotensin converting enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false}],"id":268},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"A 35-year-old woman presents to the outpatient department with complaints of fever, productive cough, and retrosternal chest pain during coughing. After the examination, the physician diagnoses her with the case of tracheitis. Which of the following is incorrect for tracheal structure?","answers":[{"option":"Epithelial lining resting on a thick basement membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroelastic membrane in deep membrane lamina propria","bool":false},{"option":"C-shape cartilage plate in adventitia","bool":true},{"option":"Seromucous glands in submucosa","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelium consists of columnar ciliated cells","bool":false}],"id":269},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which ion levels are disrupted in respiratory alkalosis?","answers":[{"option":"Ca and Na","bool":false},{"option":"Ca and K","bool":true},{"option":"K and Na","bool":false},{"option":"Mg and Na","bool":false},{"option":"Selenium","bool":false}],"id":270},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"A 35-year-old alcoholic woman presents to the outpatient department with complaints of shortness of breath and cough with green-colored and blood-stained sputum. On examination, a cold sore was found and a bronchial breath sound at the right lung base was heard. On X-ray, right lower lobe haziness is seen. What is the organism responsible for her symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Legionella","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella","bool":true}],"id":271},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"At the upper portion of the chest, esophagus and trachea will be differentiated by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"Adventitia","bool":false},{"option":"Muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Submucosa","bool":false},{"option":"Mucosa","bool":false}],"id":272},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"A man was hospitalized due to an episode of cardiac arrest. After 72 hours of stay, he developed new symptoms; cough, chest pain, and fever. What is the most probable cause?","answers":[{"option":"Community acquired pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Nosocomial pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial lung disease","bool":false}],"id":273},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is the most common lipid found in the membrane?","answers":[{"option":"Glycolipid","bool":false},{"option":"Phospholipid","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphoglycerides","bool":false},{"option":"Sphingolipid","bool":false}],"id":274},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What is the percentage of the number of the world's population infected with tuberculosis (TB)?","answers":[{"option":"33%","bool":false},{"option":"5%","bool":false},{"option":"25%","bool":true},{"option":"2%","bool":false},{"option":"10%","bool":false}],"id":275},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is not true for the surfaces of parietal pleura?","answers":[{"option":"Endothoracic","bool":true},{"option":"Diaphragmatic","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical","bool":false},{"option":"Mediastinal","bool":false},{"option":"Costal","bool":false}],"id":276},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which equation shows the pH of a solution equals to pKa when the concentration of acid and base are equal?","answers":[{"option":"Water dissociation equation","bool":false},{"option":"Hardy-Weinberg equation","bool":false},{"option":"pH log equation","bool":false},{"option":"Henderson–Hasselbalch equation","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":277},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"The mesenchyme of sclerotomes gives rise to vertebrae. The mesenchyme surrounding the neural tube gives rise to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Notochord","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebral arch","bool":true},{"option":"Ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebral body","bool":false},{"option":"Sternum","bool":false}],"id":278},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which type of emphysema is most common in smoking?","answers":[{"option":"Panacinar","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Septal","bool":false},{"option":"Paraseptal","bool":false},{"option":"Centriacinar","bool":true}],"id":279},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which groove is present on the mediastinal surface of the right lung?","answers":[{"option":"Diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Arch of aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Superior vena cava","bool":true},{"option":"Subclavian artery","bool":false},{"option":"Descending aorta","bool":false}],"id":280},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Dust cells are produced by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Eosinophils and red blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages plus erythrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages plus monocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Neutrophils and silica","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocytes and plasma cells","bool":false}],"id":281},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"How many fatty acids are found in glycophospholipids?","answers":[{"option":"One","bool":false},{"option":"Two","bool":true},{"option":"None","bool":false},{"option":"Three","bool":false},{"option":"Four","bool":false}],"id":282},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these is not an effect of atropine?","answers":[{"option":"Delirium","bool":false},{"option":"Diarrhea","bool":true},{"option":"Blurred vision","bool":false},{"option":"Restlessness","bool":false},{"option":"Hallucinations","bool":false}],"id":283},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these diseases is characterized by fever, cough, and patchy infiltrates on the lung?","answers":[{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchopneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Lung abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Lobar pneumonia","bool":false}],"id":284},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these statements is not true?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchopulmonary segment has its own artery","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchopulmonary segment can not be removed","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchopulmonary segment is supplied by segmental bronchus","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchopulmonary segment is pyramidal in shape","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchopulmonary segments share venous drainage","bool":false}],"id":285},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Cisterna chyli lies at what vertebral level?","answers":[{"option":"L1","bool":true},{"option":"T10","bool":false},{"option":"T8","bool":false},{"option":"T4","bool":false},{"option":"L3","bool":false}],"id":286},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these is a component of lung surfactant?","answers":[{"option":"Dipalmitoyl choline","bool":false},{"option":"Hyaluronic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Heparan sulfate","bool":false},{"option":"Lecithin","bool":true},{"option":"Glucocerebroside","bool":false},{"option":"Gycerol","bool":false}],"id":287},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these conditions is characterized by hyperinflation of the lungs?","answers":[{"option":"Lung cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)","bool":true},{"option":"Atelectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis","bool":false}],"id":288},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is an essential adverse effect of non-specific beta-agonists?","answers":[{"option":"Myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Tachycardia","bool":true},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac failure","bool":false},{"option":"Bradycardia","bool":false}],"id":289},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is involved in the inhibition of the 5-lipoxygenase pathway?","answers":[{"option":"Montelukast","bool":false},{"option":"Salbutamol","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Zileuton","bool":true},{"option":"Albuterol","bool":false}],"id":290},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of the following inhibits the cysteinyl leukotriene?","answers":[{"option":"Zileuton","bool":false},{"option":"Terbutaline","bool":false},{"option":"Metaproterenol","bool":false},{"option":"Albuterol","bool":false},{"option":"Montelukast","bool":true}],"id":291},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What is the normal range of partial pressure of carbon dioxide (pCO2)?","answers":[{"option":"40-45 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"30-35 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"20-15 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"40-50 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"35-45 mmHg","bool":true}],"id":292},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"The bronchial tree branches until a structure divides into 2 terminal bronchioles. Which of the following is incorrect for this structure?","answers":[{"option":"Supplies a lobule","bool":false},{"option":"Diameter is > 5mm","bool":true},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Cartilage is absent","bool":false},{"option":"Contains no goblet cells","bool":false}],"id":293},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"In terms of communication, what is meant by selective reflection?","answers":[{"option":"Feeling what the patient is feeling","bool":false},{"option":"Repeat what is patient saying from time to time","bool":false},{"option":"Moving communication from general to specific aspects","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Discuss the issue with the patient","bool":false}],"id":294},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"A 26-year-old man presents to the outpatient department with complaints of wheezing, shortness of breath, and a barrel-shaped chest. History suggested a 10-year pack history. On X-ray, hyperinflated lungs are seen. Which is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Lung cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)","bool":true}],"id":295},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"A patient comes in the outpatient department with a fracture of the 12th rib and a diaphragmatic tear. What is a characteristic feature of the fractured rib?","answers":[{"option":"Neck","bool":false},{"option":"Twisted","bool":false},{"option":"Angle","bool":false},{"option":"Single facet on head","bool":true},{"option":"Curved","bool":false}],"id":296},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What is the most common site for fracture of the 4th rib?","answers":[{"option":"Tubercle","bool":false},{"option":"Costal groove","bool":false},{"option":"Shaft","bool":false},{"option":"Neck","bool":false},{"option":"Angle","bool":true}],"id":297},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is not correct for pulmonary macrophages?","answers":[{"option":"About 1 million are swallowed everyday","bool":false},{"option":"In congestive heart failure, they are called heart failure cells","bool":false},{"option":"They remain constant in number","bool":true},{"option":"They can travel between capillaries, bronchioles and lymphatics","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":298},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"A 70-year-old man suffers from congestive heart failure. On lung tissue biopsy, black phagocytosed cells are seen. Which of the following are the cells present in the lung?","answers":[{"option":"Macrophages","bool":true},{"option":"Type 2 pneumocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Septal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Type 1 pneumocytes","bool":false}],"id":299},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"A 40-year-old alcoholic lady presents to the outpatient department with complaints of shortness of breath and cough with yellow-green sputum.  Her chest X-ray shows patchy consolidation. Which type of pneumonia is present?","answers":[{"option":"Atypical","bool":false},{"option":"Lobar","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchopulmonary","bool":true},{"option":"Interstitial","bool":false}],"id":300},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"A man presents to the nearby clinic in a state of extreme drowsiness and shortness of breath. He is at the risk of developing which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Hypokalemia","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false}],"id":301},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What kind of questions should be asked by the doctor to the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Close ended","bool":false},{"option":"Open ended","bool":true},{"option":"Semi-structured","bool":false},{"option":"Leading","bool":false},{"option":"Specific","bool":false}],"id":302},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"A young girl presents to the nearby clinic with a runny nose and a history of episodes of allergy. The doctor suspects rhinitis (inflammation). Which of the following is not correct about the condition?","answers":[{"option":"Large amount of mucus is produced","bool":false},{"option":"Capillaries are constricted","bool":true},{"option":"Vasodilation of arteries occurs","bool":false},{"option":"Enlarged venous plexus","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":303},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these is the most common finding in asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Dyspnea","bool":false},{"option":"Crackles","bool":false},{"option":"Cough","bool":false},{"option":"Wheezing","bool":true},{"option":"Orthopnea","bool":false}],"id":304},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these nodes drain the parietal pleura?","answers":[{"option":"Diaphragmatic nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Supraclavicular nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Hilar nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Parasternal nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Axillary nodes","bool":false}],"id":305},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What is the partial pressure of O2 in the left atrium?","answers":[{"option":"95 mmHg","bool":true},{"option":"100 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"104 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"60 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"80 mmHg","bool":false}],"id":306},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these cells in terminal bronchioles help against irritants?","answers":[{"option":"Type 2 pneumocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Clara cells","bool":true},{"option":"Goblet cells","bool":false},{"option":"Type 1 pneumocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Ciliated columnar cells","bool":false}],"id":307},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these organisms is the host for mycobacterium tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Dogs","bool":false},{"option":"Bats","bool":false},{"option":"Humans","bool":true},{"option":"Pigeons","bool":false},{"option":"Cattle","bool":false}],"id":308},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these does not happen during expiration?","answers":[{"option":"Lungs deflate","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragm relaxes","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragm rises","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragm contracts","bool":true},{"option":"Thoracic cavity decreases in size","bool":false}],"id":309},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Where does the needle need to be inserted for thoracocentesis?","answers":[{"option":"Upper border of the rib","bool":true},{"option":"Above the clavicle","bool":false},{"option":"Lower border of the rib","bool":false},{"option":"Through the rib","bool":false},{"option":"Central part of the intercostal space","bool":false}],"id":310},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these components is not found in the olfactory mucosa?","answers":[{"option":"Supporting cells","bool":false},{"option":"Hyaline cartilage","bool":true},{"option":"Bowman's glands","bool":false},{"option":"Bipolar neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Sustentacular cells","bool":false}],"id":311},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these is an important plasma buffer?","answers":[{"option":"Bicarbonate","bool":true},{"option":"Water","bool":false},{"option":"Ammonia","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Albumin","bool":false}],"id":312},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What is the pH of blood?","answers":[{"option":"7.4","bool":true},{"option":"7.2","bool":false},{"option":"7.7","bool":false},{"option":"7.3","bool":false},{"option":"7.5","bool":false}],"id":313},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What is the ratio of pulmonary arterial pressure to systemic pressure?","answers":[{"option":"1/4","bool":false},{"option":"1/12","bool":false},{"option":"1/8","bool":true},{"option":"2/3","bool":false},{"option":"1/2","bool":false}],"id":314},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these drugs is most useful for an anaphylactic shock?","answers":[{"option":"Phenylephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Dobutamine","bool":false},{"option":"Phentolamine","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":true},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false}],"id":315},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Sphingomyelin is made from which of these?","answers":[{"option":"Glycerol","bool":false},{"option":"Ceramide","bool":true},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Acetyl CoA","bool":false},{"option":"Arachidonic acid","bool":false}],"id":316},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"When does the primitive body cavity divide into three well-established body cavities?","answers":[{"option":"4th week","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"6th week","bool":false},{"option":"5th week","bool":false},{"option":"3rd week","bool":false}],"id":317},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these is not found in the larynx?","answers":[{"option":"Hyaline cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrocartilage","bool":true},{"option":"Elastic cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Skeletal muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Vocal cords","bool":false}],"id":318},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these structures is not related to the heart?","answers":[{"option":"Oblique sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Esophagus","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracic duct","bool":true},{"option":"Trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Right bronchus","bool":false}],"id":319},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these nerve roots gets damaged in an injury at C5/C6 level?","answers":[{"option":"C4","bool":false},{"option":"C7","bool":false},{"option":"C5","bool":false},{"option":"C8","bool":false},{"option":"C6","bool":true}],"id":320},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these organisms causes atypical pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilus influenzae","bool":false},{"option":"Kleibsella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Mycoplasma pneumoniae","bool":true}],"id":321},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"The costodiaphragmatic recess is formed between which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Sternum and diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Pleura and mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Lungs and pleural cavities","bool":true},{"option":"Lungs and vertebrae","bool":false},{"option":"Lung and mediastinum","bool":false}],"id":322},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these structures are abundant in elastic fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Larynx","bool":false},{"option":"Alveoli","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchioles","bool":false},{"option":"Trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchi","bool":false}],"id":323},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What are the primary cells infected in tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Cytotoxic T cells","bool":false},{"option":"Helper T cells","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":true},{"option":"B cells","bool":false}],"id":324},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What is the volume added and removed by the lungs in a single breath?","answers":[{"option":"Forced vital capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Total lung volume","bool":false},{"option":"Tidal volume","bool":true},{"option":"Inspiratory capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Residual volume","bool":false}],"id":325},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What is the volume remaining in the lungs after normal exhalation?","answers":[{"option":"Tidal volume","bool":false},{"option":"Expiratory capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Functional residual capacity","bool":true},{"option":"Total lung volume","bool":false},{"option":"Residual volume","bool":false}],"id":326},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What is the residual volume of the normal lungs?","answers":[{"option":"500 mL","bool":false},{"option":"1200 mL","bool":true},{"option":"800 mL","bool":false},{"option":"1500 mL","bool":false},{"option":"2000 mL","bool":false}],"id":327},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"At what level of the respiratory system, do smooth muscles completely disappear?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchi","bool":false},{"option":"Alveoli","bool":false},{"option":"Terminal bronchioles","bool":false},{"option":"Distal part of alveolar duct","bool":true},{"option":"Present throughout the respiratory system","bool":false}],"id":328},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What is the first product formed in the conversion of arachidonic acid to leukotrienes?","answers":[{"option":"5- hydroperoxy-eicosatetranoic acid","bool":true},{"option":"5-hyroxy-eicosatetranoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotriene A4","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotriene B4","bool":false},{"option":"Prostaglandin G2","bool":false}],"id":329},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"At which of these vertebral levels do the posterior and inferior borders of lungs meet?","answers":[{"option":"T6","bool":false},{"option":"T4","bool":false},{"option":"T10","bool":true},{"option":"T12","bool":false},{"option":"T8","bool":false}],"id":330},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Where does the heart lie?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Middle mediastinum","bool":true},{"option":"Pleural cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior mediastinum","bool":false}],"id":331},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What is a common cause of ischemic hypoxia?","answers":[{"option":"Hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"Vasculitis","bool":false},{"option":"Increased P02 of arterial blood","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombosis","bool":true}],"id":332},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these drugs is commonly used for eye examination?","answers":[{"option":"Opioids","bool":false},{"option":"Atropine","bool":false},{"option":"Ipratropium","bool":false},{"option":"Propranolol","bool":false},{"option":"Tropicamide","bool":true}],"id":333},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What is the best test to assess tuberculosis at a community level?","answers":[{"option":"Chest X-ray","bool":true},{"option":"Interferon gamma release assay","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculin skin test","bool":false},{"option":"Sputum culture","bool":false},{"option":"Gene Xpert","bool":false}],"id":334},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What is the most common benign tumor of the lungs?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroma","bool":false},{"option":"Hemangioma","bool":false},{"option":"Hamartoma","bool":true}],"id":335},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Where does the trachea lie?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior to the esophagus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Middle mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Superior mediastinum","bool":true}],"id":336},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which surface of the trachea is flat?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior","bool":true},{"option":"All surfaces","bool":false},{"option":"Medial","bool":false}],"id":337},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What is the lower limit of the trachea?","answers":[{"option":"Lower lobe of lungs","bool":false},{"option":"T6","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Sternal angle","bool":true},{"option":"Lung hila","bool":false}],"id":338},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these is a common upper respiratory tract infection?","answers":[{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Pharyngitis","bool":true},{"option":"Laryngitis","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiolitis","bool":false}],"id":339},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which microorganism commonly causes pneumonia in alcoholics?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilus influenzae","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Kleibsella pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false}],"id":340},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"If a Gohn focus is located in the apices of the lung, this signifies which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Secondary tuberculosis","bool":true},{"option":"Primary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Lung abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Latent tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Miliary tuberculosis","bool":false}],"id":341},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these receptors on the heart lead to increased cardiac output and contractility when activated by epinephrine?","answers":[{"option":"Beta 3","bool":false},{"option":"Beta 1","bool":true},{"option":"Alpha 2","bool":false},{"option":"Beta 2","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha 1","bool":false}],"id":342},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these is a long-acting bronchodilator useful in the treatment of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)?","answers":[{"option":"Salbutamol","bool":false},{"option":"Tiotropium","bool":true},{"option":"Ipratropium","bool":false},{"option":"Terbinafine","bool":false},{"option":"Prednisone","bool":false}],"id":343},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which one of these drugs is a phosphodiesterase inhibitor useful in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)?","answers":[{"option":"Tiotropium","bool":false},{"option":"Aminophylline","bool":true},{"option":"Zileuton","bool":false},{"option":"Long acting corticosteroid","bool":false},{"option":"Albuterol","bool":false}],"id":344},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these does not enter the thoracic inlet?","answers":[{"option":"Thymic vestiges","bool":false},{"option":"Apices of the lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Esophagus","bool":false},{"option":"5th ventral thoracic nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Trachea","bool":false}],"id":345},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these forms of tuberculosis can not be transmitted?","answers":[{"option":"Abdominal tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Primary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Miliary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Latent tuberculosis","bool":true}],"id":346},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these statements is accurate about the lung hila?","answers":[{"option":"The main bronchus is anterior to pulmonary artery and veins","bool":false},{"option":"The main bronchus is posterior to the pulmonary artery and inferior to the pulmonary veins","bool":false},{"option":"The main bronchus is posterior to the pulmonary artery and superior to the pulmonary veins","bool":true},{"option":"The main bronchus is in the middle of pulmonary artery and veins","bool":false},{"option":"The main bronchus is posterior to pulmonary veins and inferior to the pulmonary artery","bool":false}],"id":347},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"What group of lymph nodes drain the visceral pleura?","answers":[{"option":"Tracheobronchial","bool":true},{"option":"Paravertebral","bool":false},{"option":"Axillary","bool":false},{"option":"Prevertebral","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragmatic","bool":false}],"id":348},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"Which of these receptor inhibitions is useful in glaucoma?","answers":[{"option":"Beta 2","bool":true},{"option":"Alpha 2","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha 1","bool":false},{"option":"Beta 3","bool":false},{"option":"Beta 1","bool":false}],"id":349},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"How should a modern-day doctor be?","answers":[{"option":"Time-centered","bool":false},{"option":"Patient-centered","bool":true},{"option":"Judgemental","bool":false},{"option":"Wealth-centered","bool":false},{"option":"Hospital-centered","bool":false}],"id":350},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2018"],"question":"If a diabetic person is having ketonuria, this suggests an underlying?","answers":[{"option":"Inorganic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hypokalemia","bool":false}],"id":351},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A 21-year-old female is diagnosed with respiratory distress syndrome (RDS) and an arterial puncture needs to be performed on her to monitor her condition. What is the most common site for an arterial puncture?","answers":[{"option":"Tibial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Radial artery","bool":true},{"option":"Carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Ulnar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Popliteal artery","bool":false}],"id":352},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is the volume of air left in the lungs after maximal expiration?","answers":[{"option":"Inspiratory capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Inspiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Expiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Residual capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Residual volume","bool":true}],"id":353},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which beta-blocker drug is contraindicated in asthma and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)?","answers":[{"option":"Propanolol","bool":true},{"option":"Metoprolol","bool":false},{"option":"Salbutamol","bool":false},{"option":"Esmolol","bool":false},{"option":"Atenolol","bool":false}],"id":354},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"An HIV-infected woman presents to the outpatient department with fever, chills, and cough with sputum. Which of the following infections does she have?","answers":[{"option":"Atypical pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Acquired immunodeficiency syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Typical pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute respiratory distress syndrome","bool":false}],"id":355},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Elastic recoil of lungs depends on which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Elastic fibers only","bool":false},{"option":"Absence of fluid in alveoli","bool":false},{"option":"Elastic fibers and fluid in alveoli","bool":true},{"option":"Lungs have artificial tendency to collapse","bool":false},{"option":"Fluid in alveoli only","bool":false}],"id":356},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Compliance of lungs occurs due to:","answers":[{"option":"Force on pleura","bool":false},{"option":"Elastic force of lung parenchyma","bool":true},{"option":"Outward force of thoracic wall","bool":false},{"option":"Force produced by pleura","bool":false},{"option":"Force of bronchioles","bool":false}],"id":357},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"The pressure generated by surface tension in alveoli depends upon which of these?","answers":[{"option":"Directly on blood flow through lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Directly on air pressure and blood flow through lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Directly on radius of alveoli","bool":false},{"option":"Inversely on blood flow through lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Inversely upon radius of alveoli","bool":true}],"id":358},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"If the doctor completely takes over the process of care with the patient having virtually no role, what is it known as?","answers":[{"option":"Vertical model","bool":true},{"option":"Mutual participation","bool":false},{"option":"Teacher student model","bool":false},{"option":"Immutual participation","bool":false},{"option":"Horizontal model","bool":false}],"id":359},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is the cause of atypical pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Tick virus","bool":false},{"option":"HIV","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria","bool":false},{"option":"Rubella","bool":false},{"option":"Mycoplasma","bool":true}],"id":360},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is the cause of community-acquired pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Staphylococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"HIV","bool":false},{"option":"Rubella","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus influenzae","bool":false}],"id":361},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which nerve is in close proximity to the trachea?","answers":[{"option":"Suprarenal","bool":false},{"option":"Subclavian","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal","bool":true},{"option":"Left vagus","bool":false},{"option":"Left phrenic","bool":false}],"id":362},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is a non-selective beta antagonist?","answers":[{"option":"Nadolol","bool":true},{"option":"Metoprolol","bool":false},{"option":"Salbutamol","bool":false},{"option":"Atenolol","bool":false},{"option":"Bisoprolol","bool":false}],"id":363},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A tuberculosis skin test is also known as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"TB skin test","bool":false},{"option":"Positive test","bool":false},{"option":"Mantoux skin test","bool":true},{"option":"Negative test","bool":false},{"option":"Mycoplasma test","bool":false}],"id":364},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What does a positive Mantoux skin test indicate?","answers":[{"option":"No infection","bool":false},{"option":"Active disease","bool":false},{"option":"Passive disease","bool":false},{"option":"No disease","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of TB","bool":true},{"option":"Immunity to disease","bool":false}],"id":365},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which artery supplies blood to the trachea?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":true},{"option":"Common carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior thyroid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Internal thoracic artery","bool":false}],"id":366},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which nerve is compressed between the 5th and 6th cervical vertebrae?","answers":[{"option":"VII","bool":false},{"option":"X","bool":false},{"option":"V","bool":false},{"option":"IV","bool":false},{"option":"VI","bool":true}],"id":367},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which bony level do lungs end on?","answers":[{"option":"T7","bool":false},{"option":"T10","bool":true},{"option":"T12","bool":false},{"option":"T6","bool":false},{"option":"T8","bool":false}],"id":368},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is the difference between alveolar pressure and pleural pressure?","answers":[{"option":"Negative pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Transpulmonary pressure","bool":true},{"option":"Thoracic cage pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Elastic recoil","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural pressure","bool":false}],"id":369},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is present only on the left lung?","answers":[{"option":"Groove for heart","bool":false},{"option":"Groove for arch of azygous vein","bool":false},{"option":"Groove for ascending aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Groove for phrenic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Groove for subclavian artery","bool":true}],"id":370},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Where does the epithelium of the lower respiratory system arise from?","answers":[{"option":"Ectoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Endoderm of neural crest cells","bool":false},{"option":"Endoderm of midgut","bool":false},{"option":"Endoderm of foregut","bool":true},{"option":"Endoderm of nasopharynx","bool":false}],"id":371},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is a non-selective beta blocker?","answers":[{"option":"Atenolol","bool":false},{"option":"Bisoprolol","bool":false},{"option":"Metoprolol","bool":false},{"option":"Nadolol","bool":true},{"option":"Salbutamol","bool":false}],"id":372},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is the partial pressure of oxygen (pO2) in arterial blood?","answers":[{"option":"45 mm Hg","bool":false},{"option":"95 mm Hg","bool":true},{"option":"75 mm Hg","bool":false},{"option":"120 mm Hg","bool":false},{"option":"60 mm Hg","bool":false}],"id":373},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A patient with which disease has a high risk of acquiring tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic sinusitis","bool":false},{"option":"Leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes","bool":false},{"option":"Acquired immunodeficiency syndrome","bool":true}],"id":374},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"If a doctor listens to a patient's statement, then repeats and concludes it at the end, what is it called?","answers":[{"option":"Funneling","bool":false},{"option":"Selective reflection","bool":false},{"option":"Paraphrasing","bool":true},{"option":"Empathy","bool":false},{"option":"Summarizing","bool":false}],"id":375},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"If a patient suffering from pneumonia has a dry, gray lung, then he is going through which phase of pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Gray hepatization","bool":true},{"option":"Yellow hepatization","bool":false},{"option":"Resolution","bool":false},{"option":"Red hepatization","bool":false}],"id":376},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following does not pass from the midline of the thoracic inlet?","answers":[{"option":"Left brachiocephalic vein in children","bool":true},{"option":"Sternohyoid muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Esophagus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior thyroid vein","bool":false},{"option":"Thymic vestiges","bool":false}],"id":377},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which nerve gives supply to the skin of the thoracic wall?","answers":[{"option":"Intercostal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Pudendal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Cutaneous nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Phrenic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Dermal nerve","bool":false}],"id":378},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What are the muscles of inspiration?","answers":[{"option":"Serratus interior","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid","bool":false},{"option":"Mylohyoid muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Serratus anterior, sternocleidomastoid, and scalene muscles","bool":true},{"option":"Scalene muscles","bool":false}],"id":379},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which muscle is the most important in raising the ribcage?","answers":[{"option":"Serratus anterior muscle","bool":false},{"option":"External intercostal muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Mylohyoid muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Internal intercostal muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid muscle","bool":false}],"id":380},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which nerve supplies the mucus membrane of the trachea?","answers":[{"option":"External laryngeal","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal","bool":true},{"option":"Intercostal","bool":false},{"option":"Internal laryngeal","bool":false}],"id":381},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is caused by the increase in the partial pressure of oxygen?","answers":[{"option":"Increase in Hb-O2 saturation, Hb attached to CO","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in Hb-O2 saturation, Hb attached to CO","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in Hb-O2 saturation, Hb attached to oxygen","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in Hb-O2 saturation, Hb attached to oxygen","bool":true},{"option":"Increase in Hb-O2 saturation only","bool":false}],"id":382},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"In tuberculosis, the Gohn complex is formed when the lesion of the lungs travels where?","answers":[{"option":"Pleura","bool":false},{"option":"Regional lymph nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Pericardium","bool":false},{"option":"Stomach","bool":false}],"id":383},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A student has final exams due to which his breathing has increased. What condition can he develop?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":true},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false}],"id":384},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is correct about hyperemia?","answers":[{"option":"It commonly occurs due to liver cirrhosis","bool":false},{"option":"Commonly occurs due to congestive heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Increased blood flow to an organ due to vasodilation","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased outflow of blood from an organ","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":385},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following can lead to asthma in an adult?","answers":[{"option":"Alcohol consumption","bool":false},{"option":"Hormonal change","bool":false},{"option":"Food","bool":false},{"option":"Exposure to cold","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":386},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A person has bluish skin and mucus membranes, and his hemoglobin is reduced. Which of the following is correct about his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Neurogenic shock","bool":false},{"option":"Cyanosis","bool":true},{"option":"Haemorrhagic shock","bool":false},{"option":"Carbon monoxide poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":387},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Mesothelioma is associated with exposure to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Crystalline silica","bool":false},{"option":"Lead","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestos","bool":true},{"option":"Copper dust","bool":false},{"option":"Arsenic","bool":false}],"id":388},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A person came to the outpatient department. His arterial blood gases show a pH of 7.3, pCO2 of 55 mmHg, and HCO3 of 28 mEq/L. What is the most likely diagnosis in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false}],"id":389},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Asthma is commonly characterized as which of the following type of disease on the basis of etiology?","answers":[{"option":"Contiguous","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital","bool":false},{"option":"Atopic","bool":true},{"option":"Communicable","bool":false},{"option":"Autoimmune","bool":false}],"id":390},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"CO2 diffuses into the alveoli when PCO2 of which of the following is lower?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary vein","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary capillaries","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inspired air","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":391},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following interleukins is involved in eosinophil chemotaxis?","answers":[{"option":"IL-13","bool":false},{"option":"IL-5","bool":true},{"option":"IL-2","bool":false},{"option":"IL-4","bool":false},{"option":"IL-10","bool":false}],"id":392},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A 40-year-old man presents with high-grade fever (102°F), productive cough, and chest pain. Which of the following is most likely the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false}],"id":393},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is the mismatched pair?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampin: flu-like syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol: optic neuritis","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrazinamide: hypouricemia","bool":true},{"option":"Isoniazid: peripheral neuropathy","bool":false}],"id":394},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis can be cultured in which of the following medium?","answers":[{"option":"Chocolate agar","bool":false},{"option":"Lowenstein-Jensen medium","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus eosin methylene blue (EMB)","bool":false},{"option":"Blood agar","bool":false}],"id":395},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is a common symptom for cor pulmonale?","answers":[{"option":"Nocturnal/paroxysmal breathing","bool":false},{"option":"Cyanosis","bool":false},{"option":"Dyspnea","bool":true},{"option":"Cough","bool":false},{"option":"Orthopnea","bool":false}],"id":396},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Non-selective beta-blockers are contraindicated in asthma because they can lead to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Bradycardia","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchospasms","bool":true},{"option":"Tachycardia","bool":false},{"option":"Postural hypotension","bool":false},{"option":"Hypotension","bool":false}],"id":397},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is the condition in which insufficient oxygen is available for the use of tissues called?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoxemia","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxia","bool":true},{"option":"Anoxia","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":398},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following ribs is present at the level of sternal angle?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"1st","bool":false},{"option":"3rd","bool":false},{"option":"2nd","bool":true},{"option":"4th","bool":false}],"id":399},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is the hypoxia which occurs due to impaired use of oxygen by the tissues because of disturbances in the metabolic pathway?","answers":[{"option":"Anemic hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Histotoxic hypoxia","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Stagnant hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxic hypoxia","bool":false}],"id":400},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is correct about the movement of HCO3 during chloride shift?","answers":[{"option":"It moves from plasma to erythrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"It moves from intestinal lumen to plasma","bool":false},{"option":"It moves from plasma to alveolar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"It moves from erythrocytes to plasma","bool":true},{"option":"It moves from alveolar epithelium to plasma","bool":false}],"id":401},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is correct about the movement of chloride ions during chloride shift?","answers":[{"option":"It moves from plasma into erythrocytes","bool":true},{"option":"It moves from alveolar epithelium to plasma","bool":false},{"option":"It moves from intestinal lumen to plasma","bool":false},{"option":"It moves from erythrocytes to plasma","bool":false},{"option":"It moves from plasma to alveolar epithelium","bool":false}],"id":402},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is not a feature of the 4th rib?","answers":[{"option":"Tubercle","bool":false},{"option":"Groove","bool":false},{"option":"Single facet on head","bool":true},{"option":"Angle","bool":false},{"option":"Neck","bool":false}],"id":403},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is the pressure difference between visceral pleura and chest wall pleura called?","answers":[{"option":"Chest wall pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural pressure","bool":true},{"option":"Trans-pulmonary pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Trans-aortic pressure","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":404},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A young girl develops rhinitis and nasal polyps. Which of the following does not correspond to this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Vasoconstriction","bool":false},{"option":"Engorgement of vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Foreign body obstruction","bool":true},{"option":"Dust particle","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":405},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A person suffers an injury in the lower limb. After 2 weeks, he came to the hospital with complaints of dyspnea. On the chest x-ray, a wedge-shaped infarct is seen. What is most likely the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumothorax","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":true},{"option":"Pulmonary hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Atelectasis","bool":false}],"id":406},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is the type of hypoxia in which blood oxygen concentration is normal but blood is not properly supplied to tissues?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatotoxic hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Ischemic hypoxia","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Anemic hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Histotoxic hypoxia","bool":false}],"id":407},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Superiorly, lungs extend up to which structure?","answers":[{"option":"Root of neck","bool":true},{"option":"Above 2nd rib","bool":false},{"option":"Below clavicle","bool":false},{"option":"Up to the level of 1st rib","bool":false},{"option":"Up to C1 vertebra","bool":false}],"id":408},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following statements is not true about the trachea and the bronchial tree?","answers":[{"option":"Cartilage rings are present in adventitia of trachea","bool":true},{"option":"Trachea bifurcates at vertebral level T4/T5","bool":false},{"option":"Trachea begins at vertebral level C6","bool":false},{"option":"Lobar bronchi divide into segmental bronchi","bool":false},{"option":"Right main bronchus is wider and has a vertical course through the root and hilum than the left main bronchus","bool":false}],"id":409},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"How many posterior intercostal arteries are present in each intercostal space?","answers":[{"option":"3","bool":false},{"option":"1","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"4","bool":false},{"option":"2","bool":false}],"id":410},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following correctly mentions the origin of intercostal nerves?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior rami of T1-T8","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior rami of T1-T11","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior rami of T1-T12","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior rami of T5-T12","bool":false}],"id":411},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is incorrect about the posterior intercostal vein?","answers":[{"option":"There are eleven posterior intercostal veins","bool":false},{"option":"It lies superior to the posterior intercostal artery","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"It has valves","bool":false},{"option":"It lies superficial to the rib","bool":true}],"id":412},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following statements is incorrect about the anterior intercostal artery?","answers":[{"option":"It lies at the upper border of each intercostal space","bool":false},{"option":"There are 9 pairs of anterior intercostal arteries","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"It lies between pleura and internal intercostal muscles at its origin","bool":true},{"option":"There are two anterior intercostal arteries in each intercostal space","bool":false}],"id":413},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Type-1 pneumocytes are derived from which of the following cells?","answers":[{"option":"Clara cells","bool":false},{"option":"Dust cells","bool":false},{"option":"Type-2 pneumocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Goblet cells","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":414},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following does not occur during normal inspiration?","answers":[{"option":"Contraction of diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Bucket handle movement of ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Elevation of 1st rib","bool":true},{"option":"Elevation of floating ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Elevation of ribs 2-8","bool":false}],"id":415},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"How many bacilli per milliliter of specimen are required for the detection of Mycobacterium tuberculosis bacteria in stained smears?","answers":[{"option":"300 - 700","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"5,000 - 10,000","bool":true},{"option":"1,000 - 1,200","bool":false},{"option":"500 - 700","bool":false}],"id":416},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following species of mycobacterium is found in tap water?","answers":[{"option":"M. septicum","bool":false},{"option":"M. marinum","bool":true},{"option":"M. avium","bool":false},{"option":"M. bovis","bool":false},{"option":"M. kansasii","bool":false}],"id":417},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following beta blockers is used in retinal surgery?","answers":[{"option":"Propranolol","bool":false},{"option":"Tropicamide","bool":false},{"option":"Timolol","bool":true},{"option":"Albuterol","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":418},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following alpha agonists causes mydriasis?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylephrine","bool":true},{"option":"Methyl dopa","bool":false},{"option":"Clonidine","bool":false},{"option":"Guanfacine","bool":false}],"id":419},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of these drugs acts on leukotriene receptors?","answers":[{"option":"Paracetamol","bool":false},{"option":"Propanolol","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false},{"option":"Zileuton","bool":false},{"option":"Montelukast","bool":true}],"id":420},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"How many layers does the lateral plate mesoderm divide into?","answers":[{"option":"Single layer","bool":false},{"option":"Five layers","bool":false},{"option":"Two layers","bool":true},{"option":"Three layers","bool":false},{"option":"Four layers","bool":false}],"id":421},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which nerve is compressed between the C5-6 vertebrae?","answers":[{"option":"VI","bool":true},{"option":"X","bool":false},{"option":"IV","bool":false},{"option":"X","bool":false},{"option":"V","bool":false}],"id":422},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following produces surfactant?","answers":[{"option":"Type 2 pneumocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Type 1 pneumocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatocytes","bool":false}],"id":423},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A patient who comes to the emergency room with anaphylactic shock will be prescribed which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Corticosteriods","bool":false},{"option":"Noradrenaline","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":true},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false}],"id":424},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is the most common lung tumor?","answers":[{"option":"Pleural membrane carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Gastreonoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hamartoma","bool":true},{"option":"Fibroma","bool":false},{"option":"Hemangioma","bool":false}],"id":425},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A man who works as a laborer in the ship-breaking industry comes to the outpatient department with pleural plaque bilaterally in both lungs and malignant mesothelioma. What is the causative agent?","answers":[{"option":"Trioxides","bool":false},{"option":"Beryllium","bool":false},{"option":"Coal dust","bool":false},{"option":"Silica","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestos","bool":true}],"id":426},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is the simplest hydrophilic moiety in phospholipids?","answers":[{"option":"Cholestrol","bool":false},{"option":"Hydroxyl group","bool":true},{"option":"Phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Lipid","bool":false},{"option":"Sulphate","bool":false}],"id":427},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is the best X-ray to view chest lesions?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"PA view","bool":true},{"option":"AP view","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral view","bool":false},{"option":"Erect view","bool":false}],"id":428},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"The gaseous exchange takes place through the alveolar membrane. The thickness of the alveolar membrane is which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"0.2 to 2.5 milimeters","bool":false},{"option":"0.2 to 2.5 micrometers","bool":true},{"option":"0.2 to 2.5 nanometers","bool":false},{"option":"0.2 to 2.5 meters","bool":false},{"option":"0.2 to 2.5 picometers","bool":false}],"id":429},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"The Clara cells prevent lungs from collapsing through which of these?","answers":[{"option":"Regenerating new cells","bool":false},{"option":"Forming memory","bool":false},{"option":"Releasing surfactant","bool":true},{"option":"Inflating alveoli","bool":false},{"option":"Entrapping bodies","bool":false}],"id":430},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Where does the trachea get its blood supply?","answers":[{"option":"Superior thyroid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Internal thoracic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior thyroid artery","bool":true},{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid artery","bool":false}],"id":431},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of these demarcates the upper and lower respiratory tract?","answers":[{"option":"Hyoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroid cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Soft palate","bool":false},{"option":"Cricoid cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Epiglottis","bool":true}],"id":432},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"In congestive heart failure, the lungs and sputum contain heart failure cells. What are those cells?","answers":[{"option":"Alveolar macrophages and erythrocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Alveolar macrophages and basophils","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar macrophages and eosinophils","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar macrophages and neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar macrophages and monocytes","bool":false}],"id":433},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"The veins from the left main bronchus drain into which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hemiazygos vein","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory hemizygos vein","bool":true},{"option":"Azygos vein","bool":false},{"option":"Right bronchial vein","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral vein","bool":false}],"id":434},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which part of the parietal pleura ends above the first rib?","answers":[{"option":"Costomediastinal recess","bool":false},{"option":"Costodiaphragmic recess","bool":false},{"option":"Endothoracic","bool":false},{"option":"Cupula","bool":true},{"option":"Stylohyoid muscle","bool":false}],"id":435},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is carbon dioxide mainly carried as in the peripheral tissues?","answers":[{"option":"In combination with H2CO3","bool":false},{"option":"CO in the blood","bool":false},{"option":"In combination with carbonic anhydrase","bool":false},{"option":"In combination with Hb","bool":false},{"option":"HCO3- in the blood","bool":true}],"id":436},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following drugs inhibits M3 receptors?","answers":[{"option":"Porpanolol","bool":false},{"option":"Bethanechol","bool":false},{"option":"Salbutamol","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Atropine","bool":true}],"id":437},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which class of drugs is used as bronchodilators?","answers":[{"option":"Andrenergic agonists","bool":false},{"option":"Beta agonists","bool":true},{"option":"Corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-leukotriene","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-histamine","bool":false}],"id":438},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A boy who is under post-operative care after knee surgery is administered morphine 4 grams intravenously after every two hours. His respiratory rate is 8 and he is extremely drowsy. Which condition is he most likely to have?","answers":[{"option":"Hypokalemia","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperkalemia","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":true}],"id":439},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of these is incorrect about the intercostal veins?","answers":[{"option":"Supreme intercostal vein, drains into the brachiocephalic vein","bool":false},{"option":"They have valves","bool":false},{"option":"Most of them drain into the azygous vein","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior veins are 11 in number","bool":false},{"option":"Lie superficial to intercostal space","bool":true}],"id":440},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A 60-year-old lady comes into the clinic with complaints of off-and-on symptoms of asthma. She is a known case of chronic asthma. What is the reason for her recurring symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Bacterial infection","bool":false},{"option":"Viral infection","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammatory condition","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrous scarring on lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Periodioc spasm of bronchial muscle","bool":true}],"id":441},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"The diffusion of gases in the lungs decreases even at normal partial pressure due to which reason?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased lung volume","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased surface area","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased velocity","bool":false},{"option":"Solubility of gases","bool":false}],"id":442},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is the inappropriate statement regarding sclerotomes?","answers":[{"option":"They undergo process of resegmentation","bool":false},{"option":"Somites form the vertebrae","bool":false},{"option":"Somites are derived from the paraxial mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Sclerotome moves around the spinal cord during the 3rd week","bool":true},{"option":"Notochord is completely regressed in the vertebral region","bool":false}],"id":443},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of these structures does the notochord remain as in adults?","answers":[{"option":"Nucleus pulposus","bool":true},{"option":"Prechordal plate","bool":false},{"option":"Blastula","bool":false},{"option":"Notochordal plate","bool":false},{"option":"Annulus fibrosis","bool":false}],"id":444},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"The heart is an important circulatory organ. In which part of the mediastinum is the heart located?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior","bool":false},{"option":"Middle","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Superior","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior","bool":false}],"id":445},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is the commonest cause of ischemic hypoxia?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased blood flow to tissues with normal Hb and pO2","bool":true},{"option":"Thrombosis","bool":false},{"option":"Cytotoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Methemoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"Carboxyhemoglobin","bool":false}],"id":446},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"The pressure generated by surface tension in alveoli depends upon which factor?","answers":[{"option":"Directly in surface area","bool":false},{"option":"Directly on radius of alveoli","bool":false},{"option":"Inversely on blood flow through lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Directly on blood flow through lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Inversely upon radius of alveoli","bool":true}],"id":447},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A doctor listens to a patient's statement, then repeats and concludes it at the end. What is this referred to as?","answers":[{"option":"Empathy","bool":false},{"option":"Selective reflection","bool":false},{"option":"Paraphrasing","bool":true},{"option":"Funneling","bool":false},{"option":"Summarizing","bool":false}],"id":448},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A 62-year-old man presents to the emergency department with complaints of chest tightness, breathlessness, cough, and a feeling of suffocation. What is most likely to occur in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic ketoacidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":true}],"id":449},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A person had congestive heart failure and a specimen is taken from his lungs and sent for assay. Histological examination shows phagocytosing cells having dark centers. What are these cells called?","answers":[{"option":"Septal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Type 1 pneumocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Type 2 pneumocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Endothelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":true}],"id":450},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which anti-inflammatory drug is used in the long-term treatment of asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Antihistamine","bool":false},{"option":"Beclomethasone","bool":true},{"option":"Atenolol","bool":false},{"option":"Clotrimazole","bool":false},{"option":"Salbutamol","bool":false}],"id":451},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of these arteries are not branches of the descending aorta?","answers":[{"option":"Esophageal arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Mediastinal arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Pericardial arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary arteries","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior intercostal arteries","bool":false}],"id":452},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following does not occur during quiet inspiration but occurs during forced inspiration?","answers":[{"option":"Elevation of 1st rib","bool":true},{"option":"Lowering of diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Elevation of floating ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Elevation of ribs 2-6","bool":false},{"option":"Elevation of ribs 8-10","bool":false}],"id":453},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is the mechanism of action of rifampin?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibits synthesis of arbasinoglycan","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits RNA dependent DNA polymerase","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits mycolic acid synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits DNA dependent RNA polymerase","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibits glycosylation","bool":false}],"id":454},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is the type of hypoxia in which a toxic substance affects the usage of cell's oxygen such that even proper oxygen saturation of blood does not help?","answers":[{"option":"Histotoxic hypoxia","bool":true},{"option":"Hypoxic hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Circulatory hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Stagnant hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Anemic hypoxia","bool":false}],"id":455},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A woman presents to the outpatient department with fever, cough with sputum, pain in her retrosternal chest while coughing. On examination, she is clinically diagnosed as a case of tracheitis. Which statement is odd about tracheal structure?","answers":[{"option":"Epithelial lining resting on a thick basement","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelium consists of columnar ciliated cells","bool":false},{"option":"C-shaped cartilaginous plate in the adventitia","bool":true},{"option":"Seromucous gland in submucosa","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroelastic membrane in deep membrane lamina propria","bool":false}],"id":456},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is most commonly found in the lipid membrane?","answers":[{"option":"Phospholipid","bool":true},{"option":"Sphingolipid","bool":false},{"option":"Waxes","bool":false},{"option":"Cholestrol","bool":false},{"option":"Glycolipid","bool":false}],"id":457},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"The notochord forms during the 3rd week of development. In adults, which structure does it persist as?","answers":[{"option":"Vertebral arch","bool":false},{"option":"Sternum","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse process","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebral body","bool":false},{"option":"Nulceus pulposus","bool":true}],"id":458},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Vertebrae are formed from sclerotomes. The mesenchyme surrounding the neural tube forms which structure?","answers":[{"option":"Vertebral body","bool":false},{"option":"Ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebral arch","bool":true},{"option":"Notochord","bool":false},{"option":"Sternum","bool":false}],"id":459},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is the normal range of pCO2?","answers":[{"option":"35-45 mmHg","bool":true},{"option":"30-35 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"40-50 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"40-45 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"15-20 mmHg","bool":false}],"id":460},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"At what thickness does the exchange of gases occur, especially in the respiratory membrane?","answers":[{"option":"1 mm","bool":false},{"option":"2 um","bool":false},{"option":"1 m","bool":false},{"option":"5 um","bool":false},{"option":"Less than 1 um","bool":true}],"id":461},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which cells of the respiratory epithelium bear cilia?","answers":[{"option":"Basal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Cuboidal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Goblet cells","bool":false},{"option":"Brush cells","bool":false},{"option":"Columnar cells","bool":true}],"id":462},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A young man presented to the clinic with shortness of breath and a cough with copious mucus production. He is found to be infertile and has a condition called immotile cilia syndrome. Which part has the primary defect in this syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Nexin link","bool":false},{"option":"Peripheral microtubules","bool":false},{"option":"Dynein arms","bool":true},{"option":"Axoneme","bool":false},{"option":"Central pair of microtubules","bool":false}],"id":463},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A patient presents with fever, blood-stained sputum, and chest pain. Upon lab investigations, gram-positive lancet-shaped diplococci are found. Which organism is responsible?","answers":[{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella","bool":false},{"option":"Mycoplasma pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus influenzae","bool":false}],"id":464},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is the most common predisposing factor for asthma in adults?","answers":[{"option":"Food","bool":false},{"option":"Cold","bool":true},{"option":"Obesity","bool":false},{"option":"Alcohol intake","bool":false},{"option":"Hormonal changes","bool":false}],"id":465},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A 44-year-old man comes to the emergency department due to the sudden onset of shortness of breath and chest pain that started a few hours ago. Last week he had an accident and he has been immobilized since then due to left leg pain and calf swelling. The patient has no other medical condition, no addiction, and is not on any medication. His body temperature is 36 °C. His blood pressure is 90/60 mm Hg and his respiratory rate is 28 breaths per minute. His chest X-ray revealed a wedge-shaped infarct. What could be the underlying cause?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":true},{"option":"Pulmonary hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false}],"id":466},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"A person has an accident in which his rib is fractured. What is the most appropriate fracture of this rib?","answers":[{"option":"Coastal groove","bool":false},{"option":"Neck","bool":false},{"option":"Facet of head","bool":false},{"option":"Angle","bool":true},{"option":"Tubercle","bool":false}],"id":467},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is inappropriately matched?","answers":[{"option":"Streptomycin - ototoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol - optic neuritis","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampin - harmless orange color in urine","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrazinamide - hypolgycemia","bool":true},{"option":"Isoniazid - peripheral neuropathy","bool":false}],"id":468},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which factor causes an increase in the diameter of respiratory passage?","answers":[{"option":"Steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenergic antagonist","bool":false},{"option":"Water intake","bool":false},{"option":"More air entry","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":true}],"id":469},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"The thin fluid between lung pleura and chest wall pleura provides which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Atmospheric pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Pericardial pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural pressure","bool":true},{"option":"Transpulmonary pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar pressure","bool":false}],"id":470},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"What is the most common cause of pleural mesothelioma and lung cancer?","answers":[{"option":"Coal dust","bool":false},{"option":"Beryllium","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestos","bool":true},{"option":"Silica","bool":false},{"option":"Tin oxide","bool":false}],"id":471},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"After Ziehl–Neelsen staining, the acid-fast bacilli of Mycobacterium tuberculosis appear red because their cell walls contain mycolic acid. This then has what effect?","answers":[{"option":"Decolorization by acid","bool":false},{"option":"Retention of dye","bool":true},{"option":"Formation of transmembrane channel","bool":false},{"option":"Gives it hydrophilic properties","bool":false},{"option":"Causes it to take counter stain","bool":false}],"id":472},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Where are the thoracic duct, esophagus, and sympathetic trunk found?","answers":[{"option":"Superior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Middle mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior mediastinum","bool":true}],"id":473},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Which of the following receptors is responsible for the contraction of the urinary bladder?","answers":[{"option":"Nv","bool":false},{"option":"M3","bool":true},{"option":"A1","bool":false},{"option":"B2","bool":false},{"option":"A2","bool":false}],"id":474},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Where are the type 1 pneumocytes derived from?","answers":[{"option":"Epithelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Brush border cells","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Type 2 pneumocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Capillary endothelium","bool":false}],"id":475},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"The olfactory epithelium is present on which surface of the nasal cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Vibrissae","bool":false},{"option":"Medial wall","bool":false},{"option":"Floor","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral wall","bool":false},{"option":"Roof","bool":true}],"id":476},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"Chocolate agar contains which of the following substances?","answers":[{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Antibiotic","bool":false},{"option":"ADP","bool":false},{"option":"Factor H","bool":false},{"option":"Factor V","bool":true}],"id":477},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2019"],"question":"The surfactant that is produced in the respiratory epithelium which prevents collapse is produced by which of these cells?","answers":[{"option":"Epithelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Type 1 pneumocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Type 2 pneumocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Alveolar macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Claire cells","bool":false}],"id":478},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is a prime indication of a high-resolution computed tomography scan?","answers":[{"option":"Empyema","bool":false},{"option":"Lung cancer staging","bool":false},{"option":"Mediastinal abnormality","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural disease","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial lung disease","bool":true}],"id":479},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A young male presents to the outpatient department with complaints of cough and dyspnea. The physician advises a chest X-ray for further evaluation. Which of the following projections is most appropriate for him?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral view","bool":false},{"option":"Oblique view","bool":false},{"option":"Anteroposterior view","bool":false},{"option":"Apical view","bool":false},{"option":"Posteroanterior view","bool":true}],"id":480},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A person admitted to the hospital is in a coma. Analysis of arterial blood gave the following values: PCO2 25mm Hg, HCO3- 5mmol/l, and pH 7.1. What is the underlying acid-base disorder?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Mixed disorder","bool":false}],"id":481},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"The definition of obstructive pattern in pulmonary function tests is best defined by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"FVC that is less than 95% of predicted","bool":false},{"option":"Maximal mid expiratory flow is less than 75% of predicted","bool":false},{"option":"Total lung capacity that is more than 70 to 75% of predicted","bool":false},{"option":"Total lung capacity that is less than 70 to 75% of predicted","bool":false},{"option":"FEV1/FVC that is less than 70-75% of the predicted","bool":true}],"id":482},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A mother brings her 1-year-old child to the primary healthcare center with complaints of fever and cough and not being able to feed. On examination, the respiratory rate of the child is 55 breaths per minute. There is chest indrawing and wheeze present and the child is lethargic and sleepy. What is the child's classification according to the IMNCI guidelines?","answers":[{"option":"Very severe disease","bool":true},{"option":"Mild pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"No pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Cough and cold","bool":false}],"id":483},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A mother visits a primary healthcare center with her 2-month-old infant. She wants advice on how to prevent acute respiratory tract infections in her baby. Apart from immunization, which of the following is the most applicable preventative measure the doctor can advise her?","answers":[{"option":"Better hygiene","bool":false},{"option":"Breastfeeding","bool":true},{"option":"Immediate care in case of fever","bool":false},{"option":"Better nutrition","bool":false},{"option":"Control of indoor pollution","bool":false}],"id":484},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A 35-year-old factory worker comes to the outpatient department with complaints of fever, chills, and pain in the right side of his chest. He has worked in a factory for 8 years. His blood count shows raised white blood cells, normal hemoglobin, and raised ESR. What is the etiology of this condition?","answers":[{"option":"P. aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"S. aureus","bool":false},{"option":"K. pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"S. pneumoniae","bool":true}],"id":485},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A 47-year-old lady with diabetes comes to the hospital with complaints of fever and chills. The fever is associated with vomiting and cough. She explains she had the flu a week ago. Her total white blood cell count is raised and her culture shows the growth of Factor V and X. What is the causative agent of her symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"H influenza","bool":true},{"option":"E. Coli","bool":false},{"option":"P. aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"S. pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"K. pneumoniae","bool":false}],"id":486},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A 56-year-old male presents to the emergency room with severe shortness of breath, fever, and cough. The cough is productive with yellowish sputum and has been increasing for the past 2 days. He has been smoking for 25 years. He has been hospitalized twice for shortness of breath. He is taking a bronchodilator preparation twice a day. He denies chest pain or hemoptysis. His temperature is 100 F, pulse 94 beats/min, respiratory rate 25 breaths/minute, and blood pressure is 130/86 mmHg. Pulmonary function testing shows FEV1/FVC ratio to be <70% with no bronchodilator reversibility. FEV1 is <80%. A chest X-ray done 4 months ago shows a hyperinflated lung. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acute exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease","bool":true},{"option":"Pneumothorax","bool":false},{"option":"Acute asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary edema","bool":false}],"id":487},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A 3-year-old boy is brought to the emergency department with a history of swallowing a foreign body. Which of the following is the site of the respiratory passage where it is likely to get stuck?","answers":[{"option":"Right bronchus","bool":true},{"option":"Tertiary bronchiole","bool":false},{"option":"Left bronchus","bool":false},{"option":"Upper rings of trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolus","bool":false}],"id":488},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is the correct stage of maturation of lung development in which the respiratory bronchioles are formed?","answers":[{"option":"Terminal sac period","bool":false},{"option":"Period between 5-16 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudoglandular period","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar period","bool":false},{"option":"Canalicular period","bool":true}],"id":489},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"What is the amount of air that remains in the lungs after the normal tidal expiration?","answers":[{"option":"Expiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Functional residual capacity","bool":true},{"option":"Vital capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Residual volume","bool":false},{"option":"Inspiratory residual volume","bool":false}],"id":490},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"There is an overlap between chronic obstructive pulmonary diseases and their etiopathogenesis. Which of the following obstructive pulmonary disease involves the acinus?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchiolitis","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":true}],"id":491},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Clinical signs and symptoms of pulmonary embolism mimic myocardial infarction. Which of the following is the most correct method of diagnosing pulmonary embolism?","answers":[{"option":"Venography","bool":false},{"option":"ECG","bool":false},{"option":"Chest X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Radioisotope perfusion pulmonary scintigraphy","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary arteriography","bool":true}],"id":492},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A 75-year-old man is hospitalized for the past week with COVID pneumonia. He develops sudden-onset dyspnea and tachypnea. His lips appear blue and his oxygen saturation drops drastically. Chest X-ray shows bilateral diffuse infiltrates (\"white lung\"). What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Fat embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Acute bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Miliary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute respiratory distress syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Septicemia","bool":false}],"id":493},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"An 11-year-old child is brought to the clinic with a history of dry cough at night and early in the morning. She complains of her chest feeling tight and a whistling sound when she breathes out. Which of the following is true regarding this patient's condition?","answers":[{"option":"Most likely due to upper airway hyper-responsiveness to stimuli","bool":true},{"option":"Airways will be dilated up to 4 times the normal size","bool":false},{"option":"There is irreversible airway obstruction","bool":false},{"option":"Cough can be treated with cough supressants","bool":false},{"option":"Cough is due to chronic necrotizing infection of the bronchial walls","bool":false}],"id":494},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A 30-year-old man suffers a head injury after a car accident. After a few days, he suddenly develops severe hypoxia, dyspnea, and goes into respiratory failure.  What is a lung biopsy likely to show in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Acute inflammatory cells in the alveoli","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth muscle hyperplasia and excess mucous","bool":false},{"option":"Scarring and airway dilatation","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelioid cells and Langhans giant cells","bool":false},{"option":"Hyaline membranes lining the alveoli","bool":true}],"id":495},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A 30-year-old woman who has a history of rhinitis and nasal polyps presents to the clinic with complaints of repeated asthmatic attacks and urticaria. On further inquiry, she reports taking aspirin for her lower back pain. What is the most likely cause of her asthmatic attacks?","answers":[{"option":"Aspirin causes increased leukotriene production which causes bronchospam","bool":true},{"option":"Polyps in the nose predispose her to polypi in the lungs as well","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin damages her distal airways causing them to dilate","bool":false},{"option":"She most likely has a positive family history for asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal polyps and rhinitis predispose her to necrotizing bronchial infections","bool":false}],"id":496},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following ribs is characterized as an atypical but true rib?","answers":[{"option":"12","bool":false},{"option":"5","bool":false},{"option":"7","bool":false},{"option":"3","bool":false},{"option":"1","bool":true}],"id":497},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"An injury to the phrenic nerve denervates which part of the parietal pleura?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral diaphragmatic","bool":false},{"option":"Costal","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical","bool":false},{"option":"Mediastinal","bool":true},{"option":"Apical","bool":false}],"id":498},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is present in expired air?","answers":[{"option":"Residual volume","bool":false},{"option":"Only carbon dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Dead space air","bool":false},{"option":"Dead space and alveolar space air","bool":true},{"option":"Alveolar space air","bool":false}],"id":499},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Through which of the following anemia leads to hypoxia?","answers":[{"option":"Inadequate oxygen supply","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory decompensation","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperventilation","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoventilation","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased plasma protein","bool":false}],"id":500},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following cells are not present in the mucosal lining of the nasopharynx?","answers":[{"option":"Clara cells","bool":true},{"option":"Diffuse neuroendocrine cells (DNES)","bool":false},{"option":"Ciliated columnar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Serous cells","bool":false},{"option":"Goblet cells","bool":false}],"id":501},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is among the factors that obstruct effective communication?","answers":[{"option":"Reasonable eye-contact","bool":false},{"option":"Selective listening","bool":true},{"option":"Selective reflection","bool":false},{"option":"Active listening","bool":false},{"option":"Paraphrasing","bool":false}],"id":502},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is most likely to occur in the Haldane effect?","answers":[{"option":"Oxygen replaces carbon dioxide in blood","bool":true},{"option":"Oxygen replaces water in blood","bool":false},{"option":"Oxygen replaces chloride in blood","bool":false},{"option":"Oxygen replaces potassium in blood","bool":false},{"option":"Oxygen replaces hydrogen in blood","bool":false}],"id":503},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following best explains the vertical model in the doctor-patient relationship?","answers":[{"option":"Patient makes all the decisions on their own","bool":false},{"option":"Patient plays a mutual role in deciding the treatment plan","bool":false},{"option":"Doctor helps patient find their preferences","bool":false},{"option":"Doctor only provides facts to the patient","bool":false},{"option":"Doctor taking entire control which is not apparent virtually","bool":true}],"id":504},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"At what level does the pulmonary trunk bifurcate into pulmonary arteries?","answers":[{"option":"3rd costal cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"1st intercostal space","bool":false},{"option":"2nd costal cartilage","bool":true},{"option":"3rd intercostal space","bool":false},{"option":"1st costal cartilage","bool":false}],"id":505},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is best described as the pressure between the lung pleura and the chest pleura?","answers":[{"option":"Intrapulmonary pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Transpulmonary pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural pressure","bool":true},{"option":"Intrathoracic pressure","bool":false}],"id":506},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"At what vertebral level does the thoracic duct enter into the posterior mediastinum?","answers":[{"option":"T12","bool":true},{"option":"L2","bool":false},{"option":"L1","bool":false},{"option":"T8","bool":false},{"option":"T10","bool":false}],"id":507},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following best describes the chest placement during a posteroanterior (PA) view of a chest x-ray?","answers":[{"option":"Supinated against detector","bool":false},{"option":"Back towards detector","bool":false},{"option":"Face towards detector","bool":true},{"option":"Midclavicular line towards detector","bool":false},{"option":"Midaxillary line towards detector","bool":false}],"id":508},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following structures is not in the vicinity of the transverse plane present at the sternal angle and T4/T5 vertebrae?","answers":[{"option":"Left common carotid","bool":false},{"option":"Azygous vein drains into SVC","bool":false},{"option":"Right brachiocephalic trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Bifurcation of trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Right common carotid artery","bool":true}],"id":509},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following subset of cells is involved in the pathogenesis of asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Natural killer cells","bool":false},{"option":"T-helper 2 (Th2) cells","bool":true},{"option":"Monocytes","bool":false},{"option":"T-helper 1 (Th1) cells","bool":false}],"id":510},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Tobacco is known to have more than 3900 compounds in it. Which of the following is likely to cause the most damage to the body?","answers":[{"option":"Ammonia","bool":false},{"option":"Nicotine","bool":true},{"option":"Butane","bool":false},{"option":"Arsenic","bool":false},{"option":"Lead","bool":false}],"id":511},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is best defined as a condition in which ventilation decreases and the partial pressure of carbon dioxide increases?","answers":[{"option":"Compensatory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false}],"id":512},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A student has exam anxiety and starts hyperventilating. Which of the following will be the most likely outcome in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":true},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Compensatory alkalosis","bool":false}],"id":513},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is responsible for transporting the greatest amount of oxygen in the blood?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma","bool":false},{"option":"Bicarbonate ions","bool":false},{"option":"Hemoglobin","bool":true},{"option":"Albumin","bool":false}],"id":514},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is the most likely value for barometric pressure at sea level?","answers":[{"option":"76 mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"800 mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"100 mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"120 mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"760 mm of Hg","bool":true}],"id":515},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"At which vertebral level is the thoracic duct most likely to exit the posterior mediastinum?","answers":[{"option":"T10","bool":false},{"option":"T5","bool":true},{"option":"T2","bool":false},{"option":"T8","bool":false},{"option":"T12","bool":false}],"id":516},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"The mediastinal surface of the left lung has a groove for which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Ascending aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracic duct","bool":false},{"option":"Arch of azygous vein","bool":false},{"option":"Arch of aorta","bool":true},{"option":"Superior vena cava","bool":false}],"id":517},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which type of epithelium lines the olfactory epithelium?","answers":[{"option":"Simple columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudostratified columnar with glandular cells","bool":true},{"option":"Simple cuboidal","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudostratified columnar without glandular cells","bool":false}],"id":518},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is inhibited by non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs)?","answers":[{"option":"Cyclooxygenase pathway","bool":true},{"option":"Prostaglandins","bool":false},{"option":"Thromboxane A2","bool":false},{"option":"Lipooxygenase pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotrienes","bool":false}],"id":519},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is a major cause of cancer, contributing to almost 22% of cancer-related deaths worldwide?","answers":[{"option":"Environmental pollutants","bool":false},{"option":"Sun exposure","bool":false},{"option":"Tobacco","bool":true},{"option":"Radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocarbons","bool":false}],"id":520},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A 17-year-old man travels to a mountainous area and stays there for years. His body undergoes the process of acclimatization. Which of the following changes is likely to occur in his body?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased use of oxygen by tissues despite low partial pressure of oxygen","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased ventilation","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased red blood cell count","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased breathing rate","bool":false},{"option":"Increased peripheral vascularization","bool":true}],"id":521},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following best describes asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Contagious disease","bool":false},{"option":"Communicable disease","bool":false},{"option":"Atopic disease","bool":true},{"option":"Malignant disease","bool":false},{"option":"Autoimmune diease","bool":false}],"id":522},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"The visceral pleura is innervated by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Only intercostal nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Somatic nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Collateral intercostal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Autonomic nervous system (vasomotor)","bool":true},{"option":"Phrenic nerve","bool":false}],"id":523},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following cells mediate allergic response in atopic asthma?","answers":[{"option":"T helper 1 (Th1) cells","bool":false},{"option":"T helper 2 (Th2) cells","bool":true},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Monocytes","bool":false}],"id":524},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"The enzyme phospholipase A2 is involved in which of the following reactions?","answers":[{"option":"Synthesis of triacylglycerol (TAG)","bool":false},{"option":"Breakdown of sphingolipid","bool":false},{"option":"Breakdown of sphingomyelin","bool":false},{"option":"Breakdown of triacylglycerol (TAG)","bool":false},{"option":"Breakdown of phosphoglycerides","bool":true}],"id":525},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A physician examines an X-ray of the anterior thoracic wall. Which of the following structures constitute this wall?","answers":[{"option":"Intervertebral discs","bool":false},{"option":"Manubrium, body of sternum and xiphoid process","bool":true},{"option":"Intercoastal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracic vertebrae","bool":false},{"option":"Ribs","bool":false}],"id":526},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following nerves innervates the diaphragm?","answers":[{"option":"Phrenic","bool":true},{"option":"Iliohypogastric","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus","bool":false},{"option":"Intercostal","bool":false},{"option":"Subcoastal","bool":false}],"id":527},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A resident in the emergency room, while performing pleural effusion drainage, consciously inserts the needle in the 3rd intercostal space just above the inferior rib. This avoids damage to which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Visceral pleura","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal pleura","bool":false},{"option":"Intercostal nerve and vessels","bool":true},{"option":"Pericardium","bool":false}],"id":528},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"What is the value for barometric pressure at sea level?","answers":[{"option":"1 mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"1 atm","bool":true},{"option":"70 atm","bool":false},{"option":"76 atm","bool":false},{"option":"760 atm","bool":false}],"id":529},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A benign tumor originating from glandular epithelium is termed as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Papilloma","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Krukenberg tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Adenoma","bool":true},{"option":"Carcinoma","bool":false}],"id":530},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following actions of the respiratory system leads to the development of respiratory alkalosis?","answers":[{"option":"Remove excess amount of oxygen","bool":false},{"option":"Retain excess amount of hydrogen ions","bool":false},{"option":"Remove excess amount of carbon dioxide","bool":true},{"option":"Retain excess amount of oxygen","bool":false},{"option":"Retain excess amount of carbon dioxide","bool":false}],"id":531},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A patient is admitted to the hospital with severe pleuritis. The amount of proteins in the pleural fluid is likely to be more than which of the following in this case?","answers":[{"option":"3 g/L","bool":false},{"option":"5 g/L","bool":false},{"option":"10 g/L","bool":false},{"option":"20 g/L","bool":false},{"option":"30 g/L","bool":true}],"id":532},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"The contraction of which of the following muscles is not involved in inspiration?","answers":[{"option":"Scalenus anterior","bool":false},{"option":"External intercostal","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid","bool":false},{"option":"Internal intercostal","bool":true},{"option":"Serratus anterior","bool":false}],"id":533},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A 65-year-old female is admitted to the ICU. She develops chest pain 3 days later. A  chest X-ray is performed and reveals diffuse lung infiltrates. What is the most likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Interstitial disease of lung","bool":false},{"option":"Community acquired pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Nosocomial pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Lung abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Granulomatous disease of lung","bool":false}],"id":534},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A student is studying the contents of the superior mediastinum. Which of the following structures is not present in the mentioned region?","answers":[{"option":"Left common carotid","bool":false},{"option":"Arch of azygous vein","bool":false},{"option":"Right common carotid","bool":true},{"option":"Arch of aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Brachiocephalic veins","bool":false}],"id":535},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A 60-year-old female presents with complaints of difficulty in breathing particularly in the morning and during changes in position. She is coughing up a copious amount of mucus. Which of the following conditions is the most likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false}],"id":536},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"A hospitalized patient suffers from respiratory distress and difficulty breathing. Chest x-ray reveals a white lung. Which of the following is the likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS)","bool":true},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false}],"id":537},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following cells is present in the intra-alveolar septa besides pneumocytes?","answers":[{"option":"Dust cells","bool":true},{"option":"Sustentacular cells","bool":false},{"option":"Receptor cells","bool":false},{"option":"Basal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Columnar cells","bool":false}],"id":538},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2021"],"question":"Which of the following enzymes causes the breakdown of phosphoglyceride?","answers":[{"option":"Lipofructokinase","bool":false},{"option":"Sphingomyelinase","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"Phospholipase","bool":true},{"option":"Transferase","bool":false}],"id":539},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Lungs are supplied by pulmonary and bronchial vessels. Which of the following blood vessels carries poorly oxygenated blood from the heart to the lungs?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchial veins","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchial arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary veins","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary capillaries","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary arteries","bool":true}],"id":540},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"During respiratory movements, ribs act as a lever. Which of the following is the fulcrum of this lever?","answers":[{"option":"The tubercle of rib","bool":false},{"option":"At the angle of the rib","bool":false},{"option":"At the head of the rib","bool":false},{"option":"Medial to the tubercle of rib","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral to the tubercle of rib","bool":true}],"id":541},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following muscles is not involved in forced inspiration?","answers":[{"option":"Erector spinae","bool":true},{"option":"Scalenus medius","bool":false},{"option":"Scalenus anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Latissimus dorsi","bool":false},{"option":"Serratus anterior","bool":false}],"id":542},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following structures is involved in the formation of the central tendon of the diaphragm?","answers":[{"option":"Cervical somites","bool":false},{"option":"Mesentery of the esophagus","bool":false},{"option":"Pleuroperitoneal membranes","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracic somites","bool":false},{"option":"Septum transversum","bool":true}],"id":543},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following statements regarding the pleura is correct?","answers":[{"option":"It has two layers tightly adherent to each other","bool":false},{"option":"It forms the pulmonary ligament","bool":true},{"option":"It is lined by respiratory epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"The sternal line of pleural reflection is similar on right and left sides","bool":false},{"option":"It is insensitive","bool":false}],"id":544},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"The inferior vena cava passes through the diaphragm at which of the following spinal levels?","answers":[{"option":"T8","bool":true},{"option":"C7","bool":false},{"option":"L1","bool":false},{"option":"T12","bool":false},{"option":"T10","bool":false}],"id":545},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Intercostal vessels and nerve run between which of the following thoracic intercostal muscles?","answers":[{"option":"Subcostal and transversus thoracic muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Internal and innermost intercostal muscles","bool":true},{"option":"External and internal intercostal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Innermost intercostal and transversus thoracic muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Innermost intercostal and subcostal muscles","bool":false}],"id":546},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A 42-year-old woman presents to the outpatient department with complaints of pain in the medial side of the forearm and wasting of hand muscles. The consultant diagnoses a compression of the lower trunk of the brachial plexus. Which of the following causes compression of the lower trunk of the brachial plexus?","answers":[{"option":"Second rib fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical rib","bool":true},{"option":"Abdominal rib","bool":false},{"option":"First rib fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Extra vertebrae","bool":false}],"id":547},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A 35-year-old man presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of chest pain that was felt in the ribs. After examination and investigation, a diagnosis of pressure on the intercostal nerves was made which resulted in a spasm of intercostal muscles. Which of the following muscles is unaffected?","answers":[{"option":"Pectoralis major","bool":true},{"option":"Internal intercostal","bool":false},{"option":"Innermost intercostal","bool":false},{"option":"Subcostal","bool":false},{"option":"External intercostal","bool":false}],"id":548},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following maintains the patency of the trachea?","answers":[{"option":"Surface tension of water","bool":false},{"option":"Surfactant","bool":false},{"option":"Air pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudostratified ciliated epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Cartilaginous rings","bool":true}],"id":549},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following thoracic joints is incorrectly paired with its classification?","answers":[{"option":"Second to seventh sternocostal joints ---> Synovial joints","bool":false},{"option":"Interchondral joints ---> Secondary cartilaginous joints","bool":true},{"option":"Costochondral joints ---> Primary cartilaginous joints","bool":false},{"option":"Xiphisternal joint ---> Primary cartilaginous joint","bool":false},{"option":"Manubriosternal joint ---> Secondary cartilaginous joint","bool":false}],"id":550},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following parts of the parietal pleura is supplied by the phrenic nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Cervical part","bool":false},{"option":"Visceral pleura","bool":false},{"option":"Costal part","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragmatic pleura (peripheral part)","bool":false},{"option":"Mediastinal pleura","bool":true}],"id":551},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A newborn baby was observed to have continuous coughing and choking. There was an excessive amount of mucous and saliva secretion in the infant's mouth. The infant showed considerable difficulty breathing. The physician was not able to pass a catheter through the esophagus into the stomach. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Tracheal stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Tracheal atresia","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal atresia and tracheoesophageal fistula","bool":true},{"option":"Hyaline membrane disease","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenal atresia","bool":false}],"id":552},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following limits the duration of inspiration and subsequently increases the inspiratory rate?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsal respiratory group of neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Chemotaxic center","bool":false},{"option":"Apneustic center","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumotaxic center","bool":true},{"option":"Ventral respiratory group of neurons","bool":false}],"id":553},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following has a significant direct stimulatory effect on central chemoreceptors?","answers":[{"option":"Increased pH of blood","bool":false},{"option":"Increased hydrogen ions in cerebrospinal fluid","bool":true},{"option":"Decreases oxygen partial pressure of blood","bool":false},{"option":"Increased carbon dioxide in cerebrospinal fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Increased carbon dioxide in blood","bool":false}],"id":554},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Mountain climbers have found that when they ascend a mountain slowly, over a longer period of days rather than a period of hours, they breathe much more deeply and therefore can withstand far lower atmospheric oxygen concentrations than when they ascend rapidly. What is this phenomenon called?","answers":[{"option":"Modification","bool":false},{"option":"Acclimatization","bool":true},{"option":"Alteration","bool":false},{"option":"Accommodation","bool":false},{"option":"Familiarization","bool":false}],"id":555},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is the most powerful respiratory stimulus for breathing in healthy individuals?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of oxygen in tissue","bool":false},{"option":"High pH and high carbon dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in pH of blood","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in pH of blood","bool":false},{"option":"Increased carbon dioxide in blood","bool":true}],"id":556},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A patient presents to the emergency room with rib fractures. His breathing is painful so he is taking rapid, and shallow breaths. His respiratory rate is 40 breaths per minute and his tidal volume is 200 ml. What would be his minute respiratory volume?","answers":[{"option":"4600 ml/minute","bool":false},{"option":"2000 ml/minute","bool":false},{"option":"400 ml/minute","bool":false},{"option":"200 ml/minute","bool":false},{"option":"8000 ml/minute","bool":true}],"id":557},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A 32-year-old man presents to the emergency room with a complaint of having trouble breathing after he met a road traffic accident. His lung function test shows his functional residual capacity to be reduced. What does this capacity indicate?","answers":[{"option":"The amount of air remaining in the lungs after normal expiration","bool":true},{"option":"The amount of air remaining in the lungs after maximum expiration","bool":false},{"option":"Combination of inspiratory reserve volume and tidal volume","bool":false},{"option":"The amount of air expelled out after each normal expiration","bool":false},{"option":"The amount of air inspired and expired during each normal breath","bool":false}],"id":558},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following pressure differences is responsible for distention of the lungs?","answers":[{"option":"Airway opening pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Transpulmonary pressure","bool":true},{"option":"Transthoracic pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Airway closing pressure","bool":false}],"id":559},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Gases such as oxygen and carbon dioxide cross the respiratory membrane by which of the following methods?","answers":[{"option":"Passive diffusion through the lipid bilayer","bool":true},{"option":"Facilitated diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary active transport","bool":false},{"option":"Specific gas transport proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Primary active transport","bool":false}],"id":560},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following events occurs in the lungs, when the partial pressure of oxygen falls below 73 mmHg in the alveolar air?","answers":[{"option":"Damage to type I pneumocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased physiological shunt","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in nitrogen content","bool":false},{"option":"Expansion of alveoli","bool":false},{"option":"Constriction of blood vessel adjacent to alveoli","bool":true}],"id":561},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A 24-year-old man presents to the outpatient department with complaints of a runny nose; red, itchy, and watery eyes; sneezing, and cough related to post-nasal drip. A diagnosis of allergic rhinitis is made. Which of the following chemical mediators is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Ranitidine","bool":false},{"option":"Histamine","bool":true},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false},{"option":"Diphenhydramine","bool":false}],"id":562},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A person admitted to the hospital is in a coma. Analysis of arterial blood gave the following values: pCO₂ 56 mmHg, HCO₃ 25 mmol/l, and pH 7.1. What is the underlying acid-base disorder?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary edema","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":true}],"id":563},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A 4-year-old boy presents to the emergency room with complaints of malaise, lethargy, tachypnea, sore throat, abdominal pain, vomiting, and dehydration for the past week. He was known to have type I diabetes mellitus. His vitals showed a heart rate of 156 beats per minute, blood pressure of 90/55 mmHg, plasma glucose of 428.4 mg/dL, pH 6.7, pO₂ 5.2kPa, pCO₂ 4.4 kPa. The patient is diagnosed with Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). Dipalmityl phosphatidylcholine is the main constituent of pulmonary surfactants, 45% of which comes from de novo biosynthesis. Which of the following molecules give rise to the de novo synthesis of phosphatidylcholine in the lungs?","answers":[{"option":"Cytidine diacylglycerol","bool":false},{"option":"Cytidine triphosphate choline","bool":false},{"option":"Cytidine diphosphate choline","bool":true},{"option":"Cytidine phosphate choline","bool":false},{"option":"Lysophosphatidylcholine","bool":false}],"id":564},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A person admitted to the hospital is in a coma. Analysis of arterial blood gave the following values: pCO₂ 16.1 mmHg, HCO₃ 5 mmol/l, and pH 7.1. What is the underlying acid-base disorder?","answers":[{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis with partial compensation","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false}],"id":565},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is the least likely characteristic of asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Airway hyperresponsiveness","bool":false},{"option":"Increased IgG immunoglobulins","bool":true},{"option":"Mast cell activation and degranulation","bool":false},{"option":"Increased mucus production","bool":false},{"option":"Infiltration of eosinophils into the airways","bool":false}],"id":566},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Why do patients with emphysema often exhibit pursed-lip breathing?","answers":[{"option":"To prevent cyanosis and hypoperfusion","bool":false},{"option":"To regulate filling of lungs that have increased compliance","bool":false},{"option":"To avoid chest discomfort during inspiration","bool":false},{"option":"To increase airway pressure during expiration to reduce air trapping","bool":true},{"option":"Reflex response to severe breathlessness","bool":false}],"id":567},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is the most common congenital disease affecting the lungs?","answers":[{"option":"Lack of pulmonary surfactant protein B","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Tracheoesophageal fistula","bool":false},{"option":"Marfan syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital diaphragmatic hernia","bool":true}],"id":568},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following statements is most appropriate about lung diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Restrictive lung diseases are characterized by reduced expiratory flow rate","bool":false},{"option":"Restrictive lung diseases are characterized by limitation to airflow","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive lung diseases are characterized by limitation to airflow","bool":true},{"option":"Restrictive lung diseases have partial obstruction at the level of bronchi","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive lung diseases are characterized by reduced expansion of lungs","bool":false}],"id":569},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Concerning community-acquired pneumonia which of the following statements is the most appropriate?","answers":[{"option":"The incidence is 5-11 cases per 10,000 population","bool":false},{"option":"The most frequently identified organisms are gram negative bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"Symptoms always include pleurisy","bool":false},{"option":"Risk factors include age (<5, >65 years)","bool":true},{"option":"Symptoms always include hemoptysis","bool":false}],"id":570},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A 75-year-old man, hospitalized for the past week with COVID-19 pneumonia, develops a sudden onset of tachypnea and dyspnea. His lips appear blue and his oxygen saturation drops drastically. Chest X-Ray shows diffuse bilateral infiltrates (\"white lungs\"). What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acute chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute respiratory distress syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Miliary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Septicemia","bool":false},{"option":"Fat embolism","bool":false}],"id":571},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A 59-year-old man presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of frequent episodes of shortness of breath along with occasional cough with minimum sputum production for the last four years. He has been a known smoker for ten years. On chest auscultation, respiratory wheezes are heard. Chest X-Ray shows hyperinflation of both lungs. Pulmonary function tests show a decreased FEV₁/FVC ratio. Which of the following conditions is most likely to be a cause of these findings?","answers":[{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic pulmonary embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":true},{"option":"Diffuse alveolar damage","bool":false},{"option":"Restrictive lung disease","bool":false}],"id":572},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is the most helpful and preferred method of establishing the diagnosis of asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Arterial blood gases","bool":false},{"option":"Chest X-Ray","bool":false},{"option":"Pulse oximeter","bool":false},{"option":"Chest computerized tomography (CT) scan","bool":false},{"option":"Spirometry","bool":true}],"id":573},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is the single most effective test used in the DOTS strategy for the diagnosis of infective tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Chest X-Ray","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculin test","bool":false},{"option":"Sputum AFB smear microscopy","bool":true},{"option":"Gene Xpert test","bool":false},{"option":"Sputum for alpha fetoprotein (AFP) culture","bool":false}],"id":574},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A 30-year-old woman is admitted to the medical ward with a complaint of acute exacerbation of bronchial asthma- a disease that she has been suffering from for six years. She has been advised of certain pulmonary function tests. Which of the following results are expected?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary function tests are not indicated","bool":false},{"option":"FEV₁/FVC ratio is increased","bool":false},{"option":"FEV₁/FVC ratio is reduced","bool":true},{"option":"FEV₁/FVC ratio is normal","bool":false},{"option":"FEV₁ will be increased","bool":false}],"id":575},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A 4-year-old boy was brought to the outpatient department with complaints of nasal blockage and purulent discharge from the nose for four days. He is suspected to have inhaled a foreign body in the right main bronchus. Which anatomic feature of the right main bronchus favors the entry of a foreign body into it rather than the left main bronchus?","answers":[{"option":"Right main bronchus passes anterior to esophagus","bool":false},{"option":"Right main bronchus is more aligned with the trachea","bool":true},{"option":"Right main bronchus is longer","bool":false},{"option":"Right main bronchus is narrower","bool":false},{"option":"Right main bronchus is horizontal","bool":false}],"id":576},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A 40-year-old woman presents to the outpatient department with complaints of chronic cough, shortness of breath, and cyanosis. She is diagnosed with restrictive lung disease on a pulmonary function test. Which of the following findings of the pulmonary function test suggest the diagnosis of restrictive lung disease?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased FEV₁","bool":false},{"option":"FEV₁/FVC ratio is increased","bool":true},{"option":"Increased FVC","bool":false},{"option":"No change in FEV₁/FVC ratio","bool":false},{"option":"FEV₁/FVC ratio is reduced","bool":false}],"id":577},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"During a session of pleural effusion drainage, the physician asked the trainee to keep the needle just above the upper border of the lower rib. This was done to avoid injury to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Long thoracic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Intercostal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Neurovascular bundle","bool":false},{"option":"Intercostal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Intercostal artery","bool":false}],"id":578},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which ions move outside of the red blood cells in the chloride shift?","answers":[{"option":"Sodium ions","bool":false},{"option":"Chloride ions","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium ions","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium ions","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrogen carbonate ions","bool":true}],"id":579},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following parts of the respiratory tract has the maximum number of smooth muscles?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchi","bool":false},{"option":"Alveoli","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiole","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory bronchiole","bool":false},{"option":"Trachea","bool":false}],"id":580},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"The lungs receive arterial blood supply from two sources: the pulmonary arteries and the bronchial arteries. From which of the following does the right bronchial artery originate?","answers":[{"option":"Third posterior intercostal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior surface of the thoracic aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Second intercostal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior surface of the thoracic aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Upper left bronchial artery","bool":false}],"id":581},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A patient comes to the emergency department with a low-pitched, hoarse voice, and noisy breathing. On examination, left vocal cords are found to be affected. Damage to which nerve can result in these findings?","answers":[{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Internal laryngeal","bool":false},{"option":"Left recurrent laryngeal","bool":true},{"option":"Intercostal","bool":false},{"option":"External laryngeal","bool":false}],"id":582},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A 12-year-old girl presents to the emergency department with chest pain and labored breathing after falling off her bicycle. A chest x-ray reveals a fracture of the first rib. Which one of the following arteries is associated with the affected rib?","answers":[{"option":"Internal thoracic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Intercostal arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Perforating arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Subclavian artery","bool":true}],"id":583},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following pressures corresponds to the elastic forces which tend to collapse the lung?","answers":[{"option":"Pleural","bool":false},{"option":"Transpulmonary","bool":true},{"option":"Lung","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar","bool":false},{"option":"Transthoracic","bool":false}],"id":584},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"An organ that is present in children and regresses by puberty is a constituent of which of the following mediastinum?","answers":[{"option":"Middle","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior","bool":false},{"option":"Superior","bool":true}],"id":585},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Trachealis is a band of muscle that exists between the open ends of the tracheal cartilages. What is its type?","answers":[{"option":"Hyaline","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth","bool":true},{"option":"Skeletal and smooth","bool":false},{"option":"Skeletal","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac","bool":false}],"id":586},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which respiratory organ has both skeletal muscles and cartilage?","answers":[{"option":"Trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Terminal bronchiole","bool":false},{"option":"Larynx","bool":true},{"option":"Alveoli","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory bronchiole","bool":false}],"id":587},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"In which of the following conditions is a barrel-shaped chest observed on examination?","answers":[{"option":"Lung cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false}],"id":588},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"Which of the following corresponds to the total lung compliance of both lungs?","answers":[{"option":"300 ml of air/cm H₂O","bool":false},{"option":"250 ml of air/cm H₂O","bool":false},{"option":"400 ml of air/cm H₂O","bool":false},{"option":"100 ml of air/cm H₂O","bool":false},{"option":"200 ml of air/cm H₂O","bool":true}],"id":589},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"A child has difficulty breathing upon inhalation of pet dander dust and smoke. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Lung cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Nonatopic asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Atopic asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false}],"id":590},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2022"],"question":"An 81-year-old patient is repetitively hospitalized due to respiratory tract infections. What of the following is the best advice that a doctor can give him to avoid future respiratory tract infections?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumococcal and influenza vaccine","bool":true},{"option":"Washing hands and maintain hygiene","bool":false},{"option":"Adenovirus vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus influenza B vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Proper diet","bool":false}],"id":591},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A patient underwent a chest CT scan that revealed a mass in the anterior mediastinum. Among the following conditions, what is the most likely cause of the mass?","answers":[{"option":"Diaphragmatic hernia","bool":false},{"option":"Thymoma","bool":true},{"option":"Esophageal tear","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroma","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoma of bronchi","bool":false}],"id":592},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 4-year-old boy was brought to the emergency department. The mother tells that the boy has swallowed a small bead while playing. Which of the following is the most appropriate reason for this bead to enter the right lung?","answers":[{"option":"Right lung has one lobe more than left lung","bool":false},{"option":"Right lung is heavier than the left lung","bool":false},{"option":"Right bronchus is more vertically placed than the left one","bool":true},{"option":"Right lung is shorter than the left lung","bool":false},{"option":"Right bronchus is narrower than the left one","bool":false}],"id":593},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"While discussing important clinical landmarks, students consider the significant ones in\r\nrelation to the division of mediastinum. Which of the following is primarily considered a landmark to divide the mediastinum?","answers":[{"option":"Foramen of Winslow","bool":false},{"option":"Angle of louis","bool":true},{"option":"Thoracic inlet","bool":false},{"option":"12th thoracic vertebra","bool":false},{"option":"Costodiaphragmatic recess","bool":false}],"id":594},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 60-year-old patient has a profuse amount of fluid in the left pleural cavity due to \r\nacute pleurisy. Where would the fluid accumulate?","answers":[{"option":"Lingula","bool":false},{"option":"Costodiaphragmatic recess","bool":true},{"option":"Hilar reflection","bool":false},{"option":"Costomediastinal recess","bool":false},{"option":"Cupola","bool":false}],"id":595},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Which of the following branches of typical intercostal nerves arise near the angle of ribs?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior cutaneous","bool":false},{"option":"Muscular branch","bool":false},{"option":"Rami communicantes","bool":false},{"option":"Collateral","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral cutaneous","bool":false}],"id":596},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Which of the following is an incorrect statement regarding posterior intercostal arteries?","answers":[{"option":"Eleven in number on each side","bool":false},{"option":"Content of costal groove","bool":false},{"option":"Give mammary branches to the breast","bool":false},{"option":"Give right bronchial artery","bool":false},{"option":"All are branches of descending thoracic aorta","bool":true}],"id":597},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Which of the following joints of the thorax is a primary cartilaginous joint?","answers":[{"option":"Second sternocostal","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth sternocostal","bool":false},{"option":"Manubriosternal","bool":false},{"option":"Fifth sternocostal","bool":false},{"option":"First sternocostal","bool":true}],"id":598},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Which of the following pairs of ribs is classified as vertebrochondral ribs?","answers":[{"option":"10 and 11","bool":false},{"option":"2 till 7","bool":false},{"option":"1 till 7","bool":false},{"option":"8, 9 and 10","bool":true},{"option":"11 and 12","bool":false}],"id":599},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A patient comes to the chest clinic with the complaint of chest pain felt in the ribs. After examination, a diagnosis of pressure on intercostal nerves was made. This compression on intercostal nerves was leading to spasms of the muscles being innervated by these nerves. Which of the following muscles would be unaffected in this scenario?","answers":[{"option":"Innermost intercostal","bool":false},{"option":"Internal intercostal","bool":false},{"option":"Pectoralis major","bool":true},{"option":"Subcostal","bool":false},{"option":"External intercostal","bool":false}],"id":600},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"In which of the  following weeks do the terminal bronchioles become larger to form two or more respiratory bronchioles\r\nand primordial alveolar ducts are formed?","answers":[{"option":"28 to 32","bool":false},{"option":"11 to 16 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"5 to 10 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"33 to 40","bool":false},{"option":"16 to 25 weeks","bool":true}],"id":601},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Which of the following structures does not participate in forming the thoracoabdominal diaphragm?","answers":[{"option":"Mesentry of oesophagus","bool":false},{"option":"Myoblast from cervical somites","bool":false},{"option":"Pleuropericardial folds","bool":true},{"option":"Septum transversum","bool":false},{"option":"Pleuroperitoneal membrane","bool":false}],"id":602},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"The trachea is the part of the conducting portion of the respiratory system. The mucosa is lined by pseudostratified ciliated columnar epithelium. Glands in the submucosa cartilage and adventitia. Which of the following structures has the same\r\nhistological appearance as the trachea?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory bronchioles","bool":false},{"option":"Terminal bronchioles","bool":false},{"option":"Intrapulmonary bronchus","bool":false},{"option":"Pre-terminal bronchioles","bool":false},{"option":"Extrapulmonary bronchus","bool":true}],"id":603},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"During chest auscultation, a physician instructs his patient to inhale deeply. Which of the following muscles are accountable for facilitating this ventilation procedure?","answers":[{"option":"Scalenes and internal intercostals","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragm and internal intercostal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragm and external intercostal muscles","bool":true},{"option":"Rectus abdominus and internal intercostals","bool":false},{"option":"Internal and external intercostal muscles","bool":false}],"id":604},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 50-year-old smoker is diagnosed with restrictive lung disease, which affects his\r\nlung tissue's ability to expand. Which of the following is most likely to be reduced in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Tidal volume","bool":false},{"option":"Inspiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Vital capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Expiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Residual volume","bool":true}],"id":605},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A person is hiking at a high altitude mountain, where the air has a lower oxygen concentration. As a result, they experience changes in their respiratory rate and depth to adapt to the lower oxygen levels. Which of the following physiological mechanisms primarily regulates respiration in this situation?","answers":[{"option":"The somatic nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Central chemoreceptors in the medulla oblongata","bool":true},{"option":"The stretch receptors in the lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Peripheral chemoreceptors in the carotid bodies","bool":false},{"option":"The Hering-Breuer reflex","bool":false}],"id":606},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Which of the following effects on the respiratory system occurs due to parasympathetic stimulation?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchoconstriction via nicotinic receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchoconstriction via alpha 1 receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchoconstriction via muscarinic receptors","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchodilation due to acetylcholine receptor activation","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchodilation via beta 2 receptors","bool":false}],"id":607},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"In a healthy individual which one of the following is the primary regulating variable of central chemoreceptors?","answers":[{"option":"Arterial pH","bool":false},{"option":"Input from irritant receptors","bool":false},{"option":"PaO2","bool":false},{"option":"Input from stretch receptors","bool":false},{"option":"PaCO2","bool":true}],"id":608},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"An 80-year-old obese person has been diagnosed with sleep apnea, a condition\r\nwhere he experiences repeated pauses in breathing during sleep. This is primarily\r\ndue to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Overactive diaphragm muscles","bool":false},{"option":"An increase in blood oxygen levels","bool":false},{"option":"A decrease in lung compliance","bool":false},{"option":"Relaxation of pharyngeal muscles","bool":true},{"option":"A decrease in carbon dioxide levels","bool":false}],"id":609},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Repaying the oxygen debt after exercise is primarily achieved to regulate which of the following processes?","answers":[{"option":"Elevate body temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Oxygen bound with myoglobin only","bool":false},{"option":"Reconvert phosphocreatine to creatinine and phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Reconvert ATP and ADP to AMP","bool":false},{"option":"Reconvert the lactic acid back into glucose","bool":true}],"id":610},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 20-year-old patient with asthma is prescribed an inhaler that contains a bronchodilator. Which receptors are inhibited by the bronchodilator to help alleviate her asthma symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Beta-1 adrenergic","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-3 adrenergic","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-2 adrenergic","bool":false},{"option":"Nicotinic","bool":false},{"option":"Muscarinic","bool":true}],"id":611},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Following a road traffic accident, a 25-year-old young man experiences breathing difficulties. Upon arrival at the emergency department, a lung function test was conducted, revealing a reduction in his functional residual capacity. What does this reduced capacity signify?","answers":[{"option":"The volume of air that lingers in the lung after a normal exhalation","bool":true},{"option":"The volume of air expelled after a standard exhalation","bool":false},{"option":"The sum of inspiratory reserve volume and tidal volume","bool":false},{"option":"The volume of air inhaled and exhaled during a typical breath","bool":false},{"option":"The volume of air that stays in the lung after a complete exhalation","bool":false}],"id":612},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 20-year-old male presents to the emergency department with a fractured rib. The patient experiences painful breathing and thus takes rapid, shallow breaths. His respiratory rate is 40 breaths per minute with a tidal volume of 200 ml. What would be his alveolar ventilation rate?","answers":[{"option":"6000 ml/min","bool":false},{"option":"2000 ml/min","bool":true},{"option":"400 ml/min","bool":false},{"option":"200 ml/min","bool":false},{"option":"4600 ml/min","bool":false}],"id":613},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A patient with a history of chronic lung disease is experiencing decreased lung compliance. What is the primary factor contributing to this reduction in lung compliance?","answers":[{"option":"Reduced alveolar surface area","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased thoracic cage flexibility","bool":false},{"option":"Increased elastic recoil of the lungs","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased surfactant production","bool":false},{"option":"Elevated intrapleural pressure","bool":false}],"id":614},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"In which of the following conditions is cyanosis absent?","answers":[{"option":"High altitude pulmonary edema","bool":false},{"option":"Impaired gas exchange secondary to pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism leading to V/Q mismatch","bool":false},{"option":"Right to left shunt in congenital heart disease","bool":false},{"option":"Aplastic anemia with 4g/dl Hb","bool":true}],"id":615},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 45-year-old male received a penetrating stab wound on the chest wall resulting in intrapleural pressure becoming equal to atmospheric pressure. This change in the pressure would cause which one of the following effects on the lung?","answers":[{"option":"Reduced work of breathing","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased airway resistance","bool":false},{"option":"Increased surfactant","bool":false},{"option":"Increased compliance","bool":false},{"option":"Collapse of alveoli","bool":true}],"id":616},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 70-year-old male who has smoked 50 cigarettes per day for 45 years complains of shortness of breath and is diagnosed with chronic emphysema. Which of the following changes are present in this patient with respect to lung compliance, lung elastic recoil, and total lung capacity as compared to a healthy non-smoker?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased, decreased, decreased","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased, decreased, increased","bool":false},{"option":"Increased, decreased, increased","bool":true},{"option":"Increased, decreased, decreased","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased, increased, increased","bool":false}],"id":617},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 60-year-old male suffered a stroke that resulted in damage to an area that controls forced expiration during rest and exercise. Which one of the following was most likely affected in this individual?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumotaxic center","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral respiratory group","bool":true},{"option":"Pre-Botzinger complex","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal respiratory group","bool":false},{"option":"Apneustic center","bool":false}],"id":618},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A healthy 25-year-old woman reports coughing paroxysms when the temperature goes below freezing. Which of the following sensory receptors may have triggered this response?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary stretch receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Central chemoreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Juxtapulmonary capillary receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Peripheral chemoreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Irritant receptors","bool":true}],"id":619},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"During strenuous exercise, an athlete's alveolar ventilation increases to 6 L per minute while pulmonary blood flow rises to 7.5 L per minute. Which one of the following V/Q ratios is present at this moment?","answers":[{"option":"1.2","bool":false},{"option":"0.5","bool":false},{"option":"0.6","bool":false},{"option":"0.8","bool":true},{"option":"0.7","bool":false}],"id":620},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Which one of the following factors keeps the pulmonary alveoli dry under normal conditions?","answers":[{"option":"High capillary hydrostatic pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Negative interstitial fluid pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Reduced pulmonary lymph flow","bool":false},{"option":"Phagocytic activity of alveolar macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Low vapor pressure of water in inspired air","bool":true}],"id":621},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A patient has an episode of hematemesis (bloody vomiting). His Hb level is 11 gm/dl before the event of hematemesis. He is treated in a hospital. After 1 day, CBC report shows a Hb level of 10gm/dl. At this level of Hb, what is the oxygen-carrying capacity of his blood?","answers":[{"option":"12.4","bool":false},{"option":"14.6","bool":false},{"option":"10.2","bool":false},{"option":"11.8","bool":false},{"option":"13.4","bool":true}],"id":622},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Which of the following conditions leads to stagnant hypoxia?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease","bool":false},{"option":"Iron deficiency state","bool":false},{"option":"Shock and heart failure","bool":true},{"option":"Cyanide poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"CO poisoning","bool":false}],"id":623},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 45-year-old man has been experiencing chronic hypertension with muscle weakness and frequent muscle cramps despite lifestyle modifications and antihypertensive medications. On investigations, he is diagnosed with Conn's\r\nsyndrome (primary hyperaldosteronism). Which of the following biochemical characteristics is possible in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Decrease in the ratio of HCO3: H2CO3","bool":false},{"option":"Disproportionate decrease in HCO3-","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in PCO2","bool":true},{"option":"Increase in total CO content","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in H2CO3","bool":false}],"id":624},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 47-year-old female presented to the emergency with a severe asthma attack, sweating, shortness of breath, fatigue, headache, drowsiness, and confusion. On examination, she is found hyperventilating, Her arterial blood gases report showed pH = 7.20, PaCO₂ = 58 mmHg, and HCO₃⁻ = 21 mEq/L. What is the provisional diagnosis of this patient based on ABGs?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed acidosis/alkalosis","bool":false}],"id":625},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 1-day-old preterm neonate presented with complaints of tachypnea (Increased respiratory rate), respiratory distress, and cyanosis. A history of gestational diabetes mellitus was present in the mother. Which of the following is most likely\r\nfinding if the amniotic fluid was assessed after 34 weeks of gestation?","answers":[{"option":"Lecithin/sphingomyelin ratio of more than 2","bool":true},{"option":"Lecithin/sphingomyelin ratio of less than 1","bool":false},{"option":"Lecithin/sphingomyelin ratio of less than 5","bool":false},{"option":"Lecithin/sphingomyelin ratio of more than 5","bool":false},{"option":"Lecithin/sphingomyelin ratio of less than 2","bool":false}],"id":626},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"\"The enzyme responsible for the breakdown of phospholipids into fatty acids and glycerol\". The given explanation best corresponds to which of the following enzymes?","answers":[{"option":"Amylase","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphorylase","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphatidyl kinase","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphatidyl phosphorylase","bool":false},{"option":"Lipase","bool":true}],"id":627},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Slow-reacting substances of anaphylaxis (SRS-A) are an important regulator in many diseases involving inflammatory or immediate hypersensitivity reactions such as asthma. Which of the following explanations best corresponds to slow-reacting substances of anaphylaxis?","answers":[{"option":"Anti-inflammatory compound","bool":false},{"option":"Mixture of leukotrienes C4, E4, and D4","bool":true},{"option":"Cyclooxygenase pathway product","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibited by NSAIDs","bool":false},{"option":"Vasodilator","bool":false}],"id":628},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Bicarbonate buffer is an effective physiological extracellular buffer comprising carbonic acid (the proton donor) and bicarbonate (the proton acceptor). Which of the following statements about bicarbonate and its effectiveness as a buffer is accurate?","answers":[{"option":"The bicarbonate buffer is most effective at a pH of 7.0, maintaining a neutral environment in the body","bool":false},{"option":"The bicarbonate buffer is most effective at a pH of 6.1, corresponding to the pKa of carbonic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased activity of carbonic anhydrase leads to increased plasma bicarbonate concentration","bool":false},{"option":"Carbonic anhydrase is the primary enzyme that catalyzes the formation of CO2 in the bicarbonate buffer system","bool":false},{"option":"A fall in physiological pH is associated with a state of primary bicarbonate deficit due to decreased plasma bicarbonate concentration","bool":false}],"id":629},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"The presence of which of the following is the main difference between glycerophosphatides and phosphosphingoside?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmalogens","bool":false},{"option":"Lecithin","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphatides","bool":false},{"option":"Sphingosine","bool":true},{"option":"Lipositol","bool":false}],"id":630},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 32-year-old man is found unresponsive on the street and brought to the emergency department. Emergency personnel found what is presumed to be heroin and a syringe near his body. He is lethargic and cyanotic with symmetric pinpoint pupils. Vital signs are temperature 36.0°C (96.8°F); heart rate 70/min; respiratory rate 6/min; and blood pressure 100/60 mmHg. An arterial blood gas sample (ABG) is drawn in addition to the following laboratory tests:\r\nSerum Na+ = 138 mEq/L\r\nSerum Cl- = 101 mEq/L.\r\nSerum K+ = 4.0 mEq/L\r\nSerum creatinine (SCr) = 0.58 mg/dl.\r\n\r\nWhat would most likely be seen on this patient's ABG?","answers":[{"option":"Normal pH; increased PCO2; increased HCO3-","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased pH; decreased PCO2; decreased HCO3-","bool":false},{"option":"Increased pH; decreased PCO2; decreased HCO3-","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased pH; increased PCO2; increased HCO3-","bool":true},{"option":"Increased pH; increased PCO2; increased HCO3-","bool":false}],"id":631},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 35-year-old man has chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and has elevated levels of carbon dioxide in his blood, resulting in respiratory acidosis. How would his body attempt to compensate for this respiratory acidosis?","answers":[{"option":"The bicarbonate buffer system releases more bicarbonate ions","bool":true},{"option":"The respiratory rate increases to expel more carbon dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Patient's blood becomes more alkaline","bool":false},{"option":"The kidneys excrete excess bicarbonate ions","bool":false},{"option":"The kidneys will absorb H+ ions","bool":false}],"id":632},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Which of the following is the least characteristic of asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Infiltration of eosinophils in the airway","bool":false},{"option":"Mast cell activation and degranulation","bool":false},{"option":"Airway hyperresponsiveness","bool":false},{"option":"Increased mucus production","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in IgG immunoglobulins","bool":true}],"id":633},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Which of the following congenital diseases affecting the lungs is most common?","answers":[{"option":"Congenital diaphragmatic hernia","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Marfan's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Lack of pulmonary surfactant protein B","bool":false},{"option":"Tracheo-oesophageal fistula","bool":true}],"id":634},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 50-year-old man (a known patient with rhinitis and polyps) presents to your clinic with a history of repeated asthma attacks and urticaria. On further inquiry, she reports taking aspirin for her lower back pain. What is the most likely cause of her asthma attacks?","answers":[{"option":"Aspirin damages her distal airways causing them to dilate","bool":false},{"option":"Polyps in her nose also cause her to have polyps in her lungs","bool":false},{"option":"She most likely has a positive family history for asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin causes increased leukotrienes production which causes bronchospasm","bool":true},{"option":"Nasal polyps and rhinitis predispose her to necrotizing bronchial infections","bool":false}],"id":635},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Asthma is a common obstructive lung disease. It is characterized by which of the following pathological changes?","answers":[{"option":"Airway dilatation and scarring","bool":false},{"option":"Necrotizing inflammation and fibrosis of airway walls","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth muscle hyperplasia, excess mucus and inflammation","bool":true},{"option":"Airspace enlargement and wall destruction with no obvious fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammatory scarring and obliteration","bool":false}],"id":636},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Which of the following statement is correct about the lung diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Restrictive lung diseases are characterized by reduced expansion of the lung","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive lung diseases are characterized by limitation to air flow","bool":true},{"option":"Obstructive lung diseases are characterized by reduced expansion of the lung","bool":false},{"option":"Restrictive lung diseases are characterized by limitation to air flow","bool":false},{"option":"Restrictive lung diseases are characterized by reduced expiratory flow rate","bool":false}],"id":637},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Which of the following is the most appropriate regarding community-acquired pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"It mostly presents like bronchopneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Risk factors include <5 and >65 age","bool":true},{"option":"The most frequently identified organisms are gram-negative","bool":false},{"option":"Symptoms always include hemoptysis","bool":false},{"option":"Symptoms always include pleurisy","bool":false}],"id":638},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 75-year-old man has been hospitalized for the past 1 week with COVID-19 pneumonia. He develops sudden onset dyspnea and tachypnea. His lips appear blue and his oxygen saturation drops drastically. Chest x-ray shows diffuse bilateral infiltrates (white lung). What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Miliary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Fat embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Acute on chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute respiratory distress syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Septicemia","bool":false}],"id":639},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 22-year-old female presents with a persistent cough, low-grade fever, and unintentional weight loss of 5 for the past three months. She reports occasional night sweats and a family history of TB. On physical examination, lymph nodes are palpable and there are decreased breath sounds over the right upper lung field. A chest X-ray reveals a cavitary lesion in the right upper lobe. A fine needle aspiration is performed on the lymph nodes and pus is aspirated. What is the underlying process behind this pus formation?","answers":[{"option":"Caseous necrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Fibrinoid necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Coagulative necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Liquefactive necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Apoptosis","bool":false}],"id":640},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 35-year-old male presents with a persistent cough, low-grade fever, and night sweats for the past two months. He reports a history of working in a homeless shelter. Physical examination is unremarkable except for mild cervical lymphadenopathy. A chest X-ray shows infiltrates in the right upper lobe. Acid-fast staining of sputum confirms the presence of acid-fast bacilli. Which of the following mechanisms best explains the early events in the infection?","answers":[{"option":"Formation of abscesses in lung tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Production of exotoxins causing tissue damage","bool":false},{"option":"Intracellular survival within alveolar macrophages","bool":true},{"option":"Invasion and replication within RBCs","bool":false},{"option":"Development of encapsulated cysts in lung parenchyma","bool":false}],"id":641},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 28-year-old healthcare worker, recently exposed to a patient with confirmed\r\n pulmonary tuberculosis, is concerned about possible infection. She undergoes a Mantoux tuberculin skin test. Two days later, the test site revealed a 12 mm induration. What mechanism best explains the positive result of the Mantoux test?","answers":[{"option":"Delayed-type hypersensitivity reaction to tuberculin","bool":true},{"option":"Direct activation of mycobacterial antigens in the skin","bool":false},{"option":"Activation of B cells and antibody production against TB","bool":false},{"option":"Activation of neutrophils and tissue destruction","bool":false},{"option":"Immediate hypersensitivity to purified protein derivative (PPD)","bool":false}],"id":642},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 6-week-old infant presents with severe paroxysms of coughing and whooping sounds, along with posttussive emesis. The patient has not received any vaccinations yet. Bordetella pertussis infection is suspected and the patient is treated with antibiotics. Pertussis toxin, a known virulence factor of Bordetella Pertussis plays a crucial role in the pathogenesis of the disease. What is the mechanism of action of this toxin?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibition of neutrophil chemotaxis to the site of infection","bool":false},{"option":"Induction of toxin-neutralizing antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of bacterial adhesion to respiratory epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"ADP-ribosylation of G proteins, leading to increased cAMP production","bool":true},{"option":"Blockade of histamine release from mast cells","bool":false}],"id":643},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 37-year-old male with a history of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease presents with high fever, cough, and confusion. He is admitted to the hospital and a chest X-ray reveals multifocal, patchy consolidation. A diagnosis of atypical pneumonia is made. On probing, he provides a history of attending a meeting during the last week. Which of the following is the most likely cause of his illness?","answers":[{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Legionella pneumophilia","bool":true},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeriguinosa","bool":false}],"id":644},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A previously healthy 12-month-old child presents with fever, cough, and increased respiratory effort. A chest X-ray reveals a right lower lobe consolidation with pleural effusion. Sputum culture grows gram-negative coccobacillary rods on chocolate agar. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Actinobacter","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilus influenzae","bool":true},{"option":"Legionella pneumophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumonia","bool":false}],"id":645},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 40-year-old male, obese, smoker underwent surgery for a femur fracture. He stayed in the hospital for one week and was on anticoagulant therapy. At home, he suddenly developed dyspnea and cyanosis. He was taken to the hospital but could not survive. Which risk factor is least likely to be associated with his cause of death?","answers":[{"option":"Immobility","bool":false},{"option":"Recent surgery","bool":false},{"option":"Obesity","bool":false},{"option":"Age","bool":false},{"option":"Smoking","bool":true}],"id":646},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 35-year-old male with a severe, persistent cough, and expectoration of foul-smelling sputum, particularly frequent when the patient rises in the morning. He also has a history of chronic sinusitis. On chest X-ray, bronchi are dilated, bronchovascular markings are increased, pulmonary vasculature appears ill-defined, representing fibrosis. What are the conditions that predispose to this disease?","answers":[{"option":"Smoking","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital alpha-1 anti trypsin deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Atopic individual","bool":false},{"option":"Kartagener's syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Obesity","bool":false}],"id":647},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Which one of the following is a feature of Kartagener syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal dominant","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchospasm","bool":false},{"option":"Cor pulmonale","bool":true},{"option":"Atypical metaplasia","bool":false}],"id":648},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Due to its anti-inflammatory mechanism of action, which of the following medications require regular administration for the treatment of asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Tiotropium","bool":false},{"option":"Beclomethasone","bool":true},{"option":"Salmoterol","bool":false},{"option":"Albuterol","bool":false},{"option":"Salbutamol","bool":false}],"id":649},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Oral medications are popular for the treatment of asthma in children because young children may have difficulty with the proper use of aerosol inhalers. Which of the following is an orally active inhibitor of 5-lipoxygenase enzyme to inhibit leukotrienes?","answers":[{"option":"Zileuton","bool":true},{"option":"Aminophylline","bool":false},{"option":"Ipratropium","bool":false},{"option":"Albuterol","bool":false},{"option":"Montelukast","bool":false}],"id":650},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A patient is advised to take antitubercular therapy for six months. After 12 weeks of treatment, the patient complains of visual defects. Which drug is responsible for this side effect?","answers":[{"option":"Pyrizinamide","bool":false},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampin","bool":false},{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":true}],"id":651},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 49-year-old cobbler contracts severe diarrhea due to cholera. He used to drink and eat from the roadside hotels. He has a low BMI with a history of hypertension, and his personal hygiene is poor. He lives in a small space with many other workers. In the above scenario, what is the primary determinant of his acute illness?","answers":[{"option":"Poor nutrition","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes","bool":false},{"option":"Bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"Personal hygiene","bool":false},{"option":"Poverty","bool":true}],"id":652},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A young mother was informed by the birth attendant that her recently born firstborn baby has trisomy 21. The reason for the above-mentioned disease lies at what stage?","answers":[{"option":"First hour after birth","bool":false},{"option":"Organ development","bool":false},{"option":"Placenta development","bool":false},{"option":"Just before the childbirth","bool":false},{"option":"Fertilization","bool":true}],"id":653},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A type of learning in which a neutral stimulus is presented repeatedly with one that reflexively elicits a particular response so that the neutral stimulus eventually elicits the response itself is known as classical conditioning. After a certain time, the response becomes extinct but it can re-emerge after a period of time has passed with no further conditioning. What is the name for this phenomenon?","answers":[{"option":"Operant conditioning","bool":false},{"option":"Learning","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulus generalization","bool":false},{"option":"Extinction","bool":false},{"option":"Spontaneous recovery","bool":true}],"id":654},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Sarah is in a bad mood and forcefully smiles for 10 seconds. This behavior can be explained by the facial feedback hypothesis. Which of the following does this hypothesis suggest?","answers":[{"option":"None of the above","bool":false},{"option":"Once we know how we are feeling, we can change our facial expression","bool":false},{"option":"Some people disguise their emotions if they look in a mirror","bool":false},{"option":"The movement of our facial muscles can trigger emotions","bool":true},{"option":"We can judge someone else's mood by looking at their face","bool":false}],"id":655},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"The pulmonary function test of a 40-year-old male showed the following values:\r\nFEV1/FVC- 65% of predicted\r\nTLC- Normal\r\nFVC- Normal\r\nDLCO- Low\r\nWhat would be the most likely diagnosis from this PFT?","answers":[{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial lung disease","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false}],"id":656},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"A 13-year-old female presents to the outpatient department with complaints of off-and-on shortness of breath for the last few years, especially during winters along with whistling sounds. Which of the following findings on the chest examination would be the most appropriate?","answers":[{"option":"Barrel shaped chest on infection","bool":false},{"option":"Increased percussion note","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased chest expansion","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral wheezes on auscultation","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchial breath sounds on examination","bool":false}],"id":657},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Which one of the following is an example of a post-contrast CT chest?","answers":[{"option":"Post-traumatic patient","bool":false},{"option":"Suspected covid pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Staging of cancer","bool":true},{"option":"Interstitial lung disease","bool":false},{"option":"Biopsy of lung/pleural mass","bool":false}],"id":658},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Which of the following is considered a first-line treatment for the treatment of acute asthma exacerbations?","answers":[{"option":"Oral antihistamines","bool":false},{"option":"Inhaled long-acting beta-agonists","bool":false},{"option":"Inhaled short-acting beta-agonists","bool":true},{"option":"Inhaled corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotriene receptor antagonists","bool":false}],"id":659},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"In addition to oxygen saturation, which of the following parameters should be closely monitored in a patient with acute asthma exacerbation to assess disease severity?","answers":[{"option":"Total IgE","bool":false},{"option":"Forced expiratory volume in one second (FEV1)","bool":false},{"option":"Serum pro-inflammatory cytokines","bool":false},{"option":"Fractional exhaled nitric oxide (FeNO)","bool":false},{"option":"Peak expiratory flow rate (PEFR)","bool":true}],"id":660},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"What is a common trigger for acute asthma exacerbation?","answers":[{"option":"Bacterial infections","bool":true},{"option":"Smoking cessation","bool":false},{"option":"High humidity","bool":false},{"option":"Inhaled corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Emotional stress","bool":false}],"id":661},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Pulmonary surfactant is essential for life as it lines the alveoli to lower surface\r\ntension, thereby preventing atelectasis during breathing. Surfactant is enriched\r\nwith a relatively unique phospholipid. What is this unique phospholipid termed as?","answers":[{"option":"Cardiolipin","bool":false},{"option":"Triacylglycerol","bool":false},{"option":"Ceramide","bool":false},{"option":"Dipalmitoylphosphatidylcholine","bool":true},{"option":"Monopalmitoylphosphatdylethanolamine","bool":false}],"id":662},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"If the partial pressure of (PCO2) increases in a patient due to airway obstruction, what will happen to the oxygen dissociation curve?","answers":[{"option":"Shift down","bool":false},{"option":"Remain the same","bool":false},{"option":"Shift up","bool":false},{"option":"Shift to left","bool":false},{"option":"Shift to right","bool":true}],"id":663},{"info":["1st-year/respiratory/compiled","1st-year/respiratory/2023"],"question":"Which of the following correctly represents the oxygen dissociation curve?","answers":[{"option":"Linear","bool":false},{"option":"Sigmoidal","bool":true},{"option":"Parabolic","bool":false},{"option":"Wavy","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperbolic","bool":false}],"id":664}]
export default arr